<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: en | Teracy's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/categories/en/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-04-20T09:26:29+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.teracy.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Teracy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to develop Angular 2+ applications easily with Docker, angular-cli and angular-boilerplate]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2017/03/22/how-to-develop-angular-2-applications-easily-with-docker-angular-cli-and-angular-boilerplate/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-22T18:16:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2017/03/22/how-to-develop-angular-2-applications-easily-with-docker-angular-cli-and-angular-boilerplate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2017/03/22/acme101-angular-hello-world.gif" title="Acme 101 angular-hello-world" ></p>

<p>About six months ago we published
<a href="/2016/09/22/how-to-develop-angular-2-applications-easily-with-docker-and-angular-cli/">How to Develop Angular 2 Applications Easily With Docker and Angular-cli</a> which received a lot of
Angular community feedbacks and questions.</p>

<p>Six months has passed and we&rsquo;d like to share more best practices to develop Angular applications with
Docker after working on it for a while.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Received Feedbacks</h2>

<p>We received some outstanding feedbacks and questions about:</p>

<ul>
<li>Problems when running Docker images after pulling the built Docker images.</li>
<li>How to build prod Docker image and run it.</li>
<li>How to get <code>npm</code> packages into the <code>node_modules</code> to work within your IDE, editor.</li>
</ul>


<p>And in this blog post, we&rsquo;re going to solve all of them and even with more best practices.</p>

<h2>angular-boilerplate</h2>

<p>Setting up Angular projects with Docker to get it work properly is not easy. Luckily, we&rsquo;ve done
all the heavy lifting for you with the <code>angular-boilerplate</code> project.</p>

<p><code>angular-boilerplate</code> was created as a seed project that can be used to generate any new Angular
projects having Docker and CI/CD system support.</p>

<p>To generate a new Angular project, you can check out the
<a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/angular-boilerplate/blob/master/README.md">README.md</a> file to follow.</p>

<h2>angular-hello-world</h2>

<p>In this section, I&rsquo;ll introduce you the best way to set up a development environment and you can apply
it for all your projects, not just Angular projects. After some first required steps to set up
<code>acme-dev</code>, after <code>$ vagrant up</code>, you can start coding immediately, you don&rsquo;t have to learn the set
up steps at first, but defer it later.</p>

<p>Suppose that we&rsquo;re in Acme organization and we need to work on the <code>angular-hello-world</code> project.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s follow the README file here: <a href="https://github.com/acme101/angular-hello-world">https://github.com/acme101/angular-hello-world</a></p>

<p>It tells us to follow <a href="https://github.com/acme101/dev-setup/blob/master/README.md">https://github.com/acme101/dev-setup/blob/master/README.md</a></p>

<p>By setting up <code>acme-dev</code>, we can use it for all types of projects with different stacks with the same
set up workflow, it means that we can save a lot of time and effort to add more and more projects.</p>

<p>Re-using and scaling boots productivity and cost savings.</p>

<h2>Best practices</h2>

<p>By looking into the <code>angular-boilerplate</code> or <code>angular-hello-world</code>, you can see the following best
practices:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>We should build the production Docker image for production deployment.</p></li>
<li><p>We should work on dev mode on local dev.</p></li>
<li><p>We should work on prod mode on local dev.</p></li>
<li><p>We should review others' work on local dev.</p></li>
<li><p>We should use alias domains instead of fixed ports to avoid conflicts.</p></li>
<li><p>We should generate <code>node_modules</code> to work on the npm packages safely within your IDE.</p></li>
<li><p>We should use <code>yarn</code> instead <code>npm</code> as the node package manager.</p></li>
<li><p>We should test both dev and prod modes on local dev.</p></li>
<li><p>We should test both http and https modes on local dev.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>All the instruction should be updated in the README file, please follow there to apply for your
project: <a href="https://github.com/acme101/angular-hello-world/blob/develop/README.md">https://github.com/acme101/angular-hello-world/blob/develop/README.md</a></p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>All the heavy lifting and best practices are documented into the corresponding projects, that&rsquo;s how
we should do so that everyone can follow easily and we can support each other with ease, too.</p>

<p>Hopefully, this will help you a lot with your Angular projects and any other projects that you can
apply similarly.</p>

<p>Happy hacking and don&rsquo;t forget to let us know your feedbacks and questions by leaving your comments!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming event: Productive development environment with teracy-dev]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2017/02/17/upcoming-event-productive-development-environment-with-teracy-dev/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-17T09:41:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2017/02/17/upcoming-event-productive-development-environment-with-teracy-dev</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2017/02/17/opentour01-productive-development-environment-teracy-dev.jpg" title="Productive development environment with teracy-dev" ></p>

<p>We are very excited about an upcoming event with the topic &ldquo;Productive development environment with teracy-dev&rdquo;
presented by Hoat Le, Co-founder, and CEO of Teracy. The event will be held on Thursday, February
23 at 6:30 PM &ndash; 9:30 PM at Toong Hoang Dao Thuy (25T2 Hoang Dao Thuy, Ha Noi). This is
the first event in the series of OpenTour&rsquo;s activities.</p>

<p>OpenTour is started from the idea of ​​collaboration, and help each other of three open source communities in
Vietnam, including OpenCPS, Vietnam OpenStack, and Docker Hanoi. OpenTour is a series of activities
and events aiming at building Vietnamese FOSS ecosystem, building a network of FOSS experts to promote
the use, application and development of FOSS in Vietnam, especially for ​​ICT enterprises
and training institutions, on the base of absorbing ideas and activity patterns of the FOSS community
in the world, and through shared activities and promoting.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><strong>Agenda</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Introduce about OpenTour</p></li>
<li><p>teracy-dev: <a href="/2016/12/20/teracy-dev-the-only-truly-universal-productive-development-platform-with-docker-on-macos-linux-and-windows/">the only truly universal productive development platform with Docker on macOS, Linux, and Windows for developers</a>.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Introduce about teracy-dev</p></li>
<li><p>The existing problems that many developers are struggling:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>The problems when there was no Docker yet</p></li>
<li><p>The problems when there was no teracy-dev yet</p></li>
<li><p>The approaches and solutions for these problems with teracy-dev</p></li>
<li><p>The 4-year story of teracy-dev</p></li>
<li><p>The Docker workflow with teracy-dev</p></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>teracy-dev demo with the real projects</p></li>
<li><p>Questions and Answers</p></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Join us! To have more details and register to join the event, please see the details at <a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/979555312146106/.">https://www.facebook.com/events/979555312146106/.</a>
It&rsquo;s our honor to have your presence at this event. See you there!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[teracy-dev v0.5.0-b1 release]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2017/02/14/teracy-dev-v0-5-0-b1-release/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-14T12:41:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2017/02/14/teracy-dev-v0-5-0-b1-release</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;re very happy to announce our so long awaiting major release of teracy-dev, the v0.5.0-b1 release
that introduces lots of features and changes, high performance with Docker workflow as the default.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>v0.5.0-b1</h2>

<p>This is the beta 1 release of v0.5.0, what does it mean? By following the
<a href="http://dev.teracy.org/docs/semantic_versioning.html">semantic versioning guide</a>, it means:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>features completed, only minor bugs are expected. Avoid refactoring here, just fix bugs</p></blockquote></p>

<p>This v0.5.0-b1 release is tested with all our projects and our clients' projects, so we can guarantee
that the release has a very high quality and stability that you can use it for everyday projects.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re still lacking lots of documentation guides for users to explore and leverage all the supported
features more easily.</p>

<h2>Changes</h2>

<p>This major release includes lots of features and improvements:</p>

<ul>
<li>high performance on Windows, especially file syncing</li>
<li>Docker workflow out of the box, can use any versions of docker, docker-compose</li>
<li>support all type of provisioners configurations</li>
<li>use public_network by default</li>
<li>config override the object within array</li>
<li>Vagrantfile-ext support</li>
<li>use rsync as the default sync mechanism (with the support from vagrant-gatling-rsync and
vagrant-rsync-back plugins)</li>
<li>reverse proxy support with /etc/hosts update for auto domain management</li>
<li>auto vagrant plugins installation support</li>
</ul>


<p>There are more that you should explore yourselves when using <code>teracy-dev</code> for a while.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s next?</h2>

<p>We&rsquo;re working hard to add more documentations and guides. We&rsquo;ll fix bugs if any.</p>

<p>After v0.5.0 final is release, we&rsquo;ll take on the next major release v0.6.0 that follow our
<a href="/2016/08/19/teracy-dev-vision/">teracy-dev&rsquo;s vision</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>teracy-dev is the best universal development tool for everyone.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll take all the feedback from v0.5.0 usage to continue making <code>teracy-dev</code> better and greater.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t hesitate to use <a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/dev">teracy-dev v0.5.0-b1</a> for your everyday
projects from today by getting started with <a href="http://dev.teracy.org/docs/getting_started.html">http://dev.teracy.org/docs/getting_started.html</a></p>

<p>If you have any feedbacks or problems, you&rsquo;re welcome to create issues for the project at
<a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/dev/issues">https://github.com/teracyhq/dev/issues</a></p>

<p>Enjoy and happy hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[teracy-dev - the only truly universal productive development platform with Docker on macOS, Linux and Windows]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2016/12/20/teracy-dev-the-only-truly-universal-productive-development-platform-with-docker-on-macos-linux-and-windows/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-20T11:13:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2016/12/20/teracy-dev-the-only-truly-universal-productive-development-platform-with-docker-on-macos-linux-and-windows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Docker is great to work with, it solves a lot of problems on development, distribution, and production
deployment.</p>

<p>Why Docker?  You can find the answer here:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://thenewstack.io/why-did-docker-catch-on-quickly-and-why-is-it-so-interesting/">http://thenewstack.io/why-did-docker-catch-on-quickly-and-why-is-it-so-interesting/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thenewstack.io/hypervisors-container-era/">http://thenewstack.io/hypervisors-container-era/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.codeship.com/why-docker/">https://blog.codeship.com/why-docker/</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Docker works great on Linux, however, it&rsquo;s very challenging to make it work universal and consistent on
Mac and Windows. There are lots of efforts to solve this problem, from Docker themselves and from
Docker community, too. However, we haven&rsquo;t achieved that stage yet (until <code>teracy-dev</code>).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>These are some of the problems that Docker community has to deal with on Mac and Windows:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>No consistent universal development environment and workflow on Linux, Windows, Mac. This is a very
important factor for team collaboration so that anyone from any OS platforms could collaborate and help
each other with no differences in the development environment.</p></li>
<li><p>Mounted volumes on VirtualBox use vboxsf, which is extremely slow. This is true for Boot2Docker and
Vagrant default file sync mechanism on Virtualbox.</p></li>
<li><p>Native Docker applications offered by Docker:</p>

<ul>
<li>Slow on Mac: <a href="https://github.com/docker/for-mac/issues/77">https://github.com/docker/for-mac/issues/77</a></li>
<li>Only recent latest versions of Window 10 (&ldquo;Build 10586 or later&rdquo;) are supported</li>
<li>Slow on Windows: <a href="https://github.com/docker/for-win/issues/188">https://github.com/docker/for-win/issues/188</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>File watching is broken on VirtualBox since vboxsf does not trigger the inotify file watching
mechanism. <code>nodemon</code>, hello?</p></li>
</ul>


<p>There are a lot of Docker community projects trying to solve those problems:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/brikis98/docker-osx-dev">https://github.com/brikis98/docker-osx-dev</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/blinkreaction/boot2docker-vagrant">https://github.com/blinkreaction/boot2docker-vagrant</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/codekitchen/dinghy">https://github.com/codekitchen/dinghy</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/leighmcculloch/docker-unison">https://github.com/leighmcculloch/docker-unison</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/gansbrest/hodor">https://github.com/gansbrest/hodor</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/adlogix/docker-machine-nfs">https://github.com/adlogix/docker-machine-nfs</a></li>
<li>others&hellip;</li>
</ul>


<p>However, those existing projects do not really resolve all the problems or do not reflect
our vision for a productive development platform.</p>

<p>You can check out our <a href="/2016/08/19/teracy-dev-vision/">vision for teracy-dev</a> for such the
productive development platform.</p>

<p>That is the reason why we created <code>teracy-dev</code>. We&rsquo;ve been using and loving it for more than 3 years
and counting.</p>

<p><code>teracy-dev</code> reflects our vision for a truly universal productive development platform that anyone can
use to develop software easily. It&rsquo;s very easy to customize any OS that you can use
for your VM. It brings development and production environment closer and closer.</p>

<p>It is very important for a distributed team like us to work with everyone from different teams all
over the world on different projects with different stacks and <code>teracy-dev</code> helps us a lot.</p>

<p>Moreover, <code>teracy-dev</code> is not tightly coupled with anything, you&rsquo;re free to choose anything to build
up your development VM machine. You can choose different OS platforms, choose different software packages to
be automatically installed with the help of different configuration management tools. It&rsquo;s up
to you to choose anything other than default settings.</p>

<p>With default settings, <code>teracy-dev</code> chooses Ubuntu as the base OS with <code>docker</code> and <code>docker-compose</code>
installed to start developing software with Docker right away after <code>$ vagrant up</code>.</p>

<p>teracy-dev v0.5.0 is leveraging Docker for development as we believe in the future of containers
and Docker.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s have some comparisons between <code>teracy-dev</code> and other solutions:</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>   Criteria                         </th>
<th> teracy-dev </th>
<th> docker-osx-dev </th>
<th> Docker Toolbox </th>
<th> Docker native app</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>same workflow on Linux, Mac, Windows</td>
<td>    ✅      </td>
<td>       ❌       </td>
<td>     ❌        </td>
<td>       ❌          </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>native speed on mounted volumes     </td>
<td>    ✅      </td>
<td>       ✅       </td>
<td>     ❌        </td>
<td>       ❌          </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2-way file sync                     </td>
<td>    ✅      </td>
<td>       ❌       </td>
<td>     ✅        </td>
<td>       ✅          </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>file watching (inotify)             </td>
<td>    ✅      </td>
<td>       ✅       </td>
<td>     ❌        </td>
<td>       ✅          </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>open source                         </td>
<td>    ✅      </td>
<td>       ✅       </td>
<td>     ✅        </td>
<td>       ❌          </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>customization                       </td>
<td>    ✅      </td>
<td>       🚫       </td>
<td>     🚫        </td>
<td>       ❌          </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<p>✅: fully support</p>

<p>❌: no or partial support</p>

<p>🚫: can be achieved but not encouraged</p>

<p>Let me explain the criteria:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>&ldquo;same workflow on Linux, Mac, Windows&rdquo;: the usage should be the same on Mac, Linux, Windows.
Docker native app only supports >= Windows 10, that&rsquo;s why it&rsquo;s marked as ❌.</p></li>
<li><p>&ldquo;native speed on mounted volumes&rdquo;: the speed should be as fast and native as on Linux</p></li>
<li><p>&ldquo;2-way file sync&rdquo;: for syncing back and forth on mounted volumes, this is mandatory for development</p></li>
<li><p>&ldquo;file watching (inotify)&rdquo;: for auto reload when files change</p></li>
<li><p>&ldquo;customization&rdquo;: you have full control and are encouraged to change anything that you want to
suit your need, no hidden stuff, no lock-in and can still upgrade seamlessly.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Let&rsquo;s see what the same workflow means when developing a simple hello world <code>nodejs</code> application
from scratch with teracy-dev by watching the following videos:</p>

<p>On Linux (Ubuntu):</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="630" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ze8p9imprgk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>On Windows:</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="630" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2200zvxIdAs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>On macOS:</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="630" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XF-FQQKG8PA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>They all contain the same steps, that&rsquo;s the meaning of the &ldquo;same workflow&rdquo;.</p>

<p><code>teracy-dev</code> is not perfect, though. There are some improvements that we&rsquo;d like to address.</p>

<p>The first thing we&rsquo;d like to improve is to reduce the setup time. It takes time (around 20-30 mins)
to download the vagrant box (Ubuntu 16.04) for the first time. This is for the first time only, however.
After the first time, you can destroy and provision the same VM within some minutes. We could use
some other smaller boxes (for example, boot2docker base box) but we&rsquo;d like to stick to the most popular
Linux OS that is widely used in production. We try to make development and production environment as
close as possible. This is by default, you can choose different base boxes as you wish.</p>

<p><code>teracy-dev</code> v0.5.0 is under preview stage, we need to add more documentation and get more community
feedback.</p>

<p><code>teracy-dev</code> is created to give back to open source community as we learn and get a lot from our amazing
open source community.</p>

<p>And we need you, please try and let us know your feedback and we&rsquo;ll together fix any problems.</p>

<p>You should get started with <code>teracy-dev</code> here: <a href="http://dev.teracy.org/docs/develop/getting_started.html">http://dev.teracy.org/docs/develop/getting_started.html</a></p>

<p>In summary, <code>teracy-dev</code> brings <code>Docker</code> closer to <code>Vagrant</code> = love.</p>

<p>Thank you and happy hacking with <a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/dev">teracy-dev</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to develop and deploy React applications easily and fast with Webpack, ES6+ and Docker]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2016/11/07/how-to-develop-and-deploy-react-applications-easily-and-fast-with-webpack-es6-plus-and-docker/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-07T07:18:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2016/11/07/how-to-develop-and-deploy-react-applications-easily-and-fast-with-webpack-es6-plus-and-docker</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2016/11/07/react-development.gif" title="React Project Development" ></p>

<p>React is an awesome library to work with, however, we must pick up other libraries to build up a
robust application such as redux, redux-connect, server side rendering, redux-form, etc. After that,
we must organize the application structure with best practices to develop and deploy it. Doing all
these tasks requires some good experiences, so it&rsquo;s very difficult for a newbie. Good news is that there
are many starter boilerplate projects out there for us to choose. And today we&rsquo;d like to introduce
you a starter React boilerplate for faster development and deployment.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>There is a good starter React boilerplate with the following outstanding batteries included:</p>

<ul>
<li>Universal rendering (both client and server side rendering from the same client side code)</li>
<li>Babel for ES6+ for writing modern JS syntax today</li>
<li>Webpack for bundling, hot module reloading</li>
<li>Redux, Redux Dev Tools, redux-form, React Router</li>
<li>ESLint consistent style checking</li>
<li>Unit testing</li>
<li>bootstrap and font-awesome</li>
<li>And many other cool things</li>
</ul>


<p>However, the project is not active anymore, so we decided to fork and update it a bit to work with
Docker easier and faster. Let&rsquo;s get started with
<a href="https://github.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example">https://github.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example</a> then.</p>

<h2>Prerequisites</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/2016/11/07/react-prerequisites.gif" title="React Project Prerequisites" ></p>

<p>Make sure you have the following softwares installed:</p>

<ul>
<li>git</li>
<li>docker</li>
<li>docker-compose</li>
</ul>


<p>Make sure that docker and docker-compose are available by checking <code>git version</code>, <code>docker info</code> and
<code>docker-compose version</code> as following:</p>

<p><code>bash
$ git version
git version 2.10.2
</code></p>

<p><code>bash
$ docker info
Containers: 9
Running: 1
Paused: 0
Stopped: 8
Images: 216
Server Version: 1.12.1
Storage Driver: aufs
Root Dir: /var/lib/docker/aufs
Backing Filesystem: extfs
Dirs: 244
Dirperm1 Supported: true
Logging Driver: json-file
Cgroup Driver: cgroupfs
Plugins:
Volume: local
Network: host bridge null overlay
Swarm: inactive
Runtimes: runc
Default Runtime: runc
Security Options: seccomp
Kernel Version: 4.4.20-moby
Operating System: Alpine Linux v3.4
OSType: linux
Architecture: x86_64
CPUs: 2
Total Memory: 1.953 GiB
Name: moby
ID: W2PL:SOAQ:Y24X:VTFK:2Z3X:3CON:HWRK:7EMB:E2D4:EAPJ:NSKY:YHJ2
Docker Root Dir: /var/lib/docker
Debug Mode (client): false
Debug Mode (server): true
File Descriptors: 20
Goroutines: 34
System Time: 2016-11-07T07:45:16.819335883Z
EventsListeners: 1
No Proxy: *.local, 169.254/16
Username: hoatle
Registry: https://index.docker.io/v1/
Insecure Registries:
127.0.0.0/8
</code></p>

<p><code>bash
$ docker-compose version
docker-compose version 1.8.0, build f3628c7
docker-py version: 1.9.0
CPython version: 2.7.9
OpenSSL version: OpenSSL 1.0.2h 3 May 2016
</code></p>

<p>If you get the similar output, you&rsquo;re good to go to the next step.</p>

<h2>Git clone the project</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/2016/11/07/react-clone.gif" title="React Project Git Clone" ></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re developing a React application named: &ldquo;my-app&rdquo;. Let&rsquo;s clone the starter project first:</p>

<p><code>bash
$ mkdir -p ~/teracy-dev/workspace
$ cd ~/teracy-dev/workspace
$ git clone https://github.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example.git my-app
</code></p>

<h2>Development</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/2016/11/07/react-development.gif" title="React Project Development" ></p>

<p>Docker is really awesome to create an isolated consistent development and deployment environment and
it&rsquo;s super fast, too. We&rsquo;re leveraging Docker and Docker workflow for all our projects at Teracy,
both internal and outsourcing projects.
After cloning the starter project, let&rsquo;s start developing with:</p>

<p><code>bash
$ cd ~/teracy-dev/workspace/my-app
$ docker-compose pull &amp;&amp; docker-compose up
</code></p>

<p>If you get the following error output:</p>

<p><code>bash
ERROR: for dev Cannot start service dev: driver failed programming external connectivity on endpoint myapp_dev_1 (e2105083bdacaf5bb0684aa7a34ae0dc92b20cc748a31491368c7afa3e51da30): Error starting userland proxy: Bind for 0.0.0.0:3000 failed: port is already allocated
ERROR: Encountered errors while bringing up the project.
</code></p>

<p>then make sure the port 3000 is available for &ldquo;my-app&rdquo; to use.</p>

<p>If you get the following output:</p>

<p><code>bash
$ docker-compose pull &amp;&amp; docker-compose up
Pulling dev (hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example:dev_latest)...
dev_latest: Pulling from hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example
43c265008fae: Already exists
af36d2c7a148: Already exists
143e9d501644: Already exists
df720fc8e4f1: Already exists
eae19baa28ff: Already exists
9004de327d6a: Already exists
753292cc4b91: Already exists
21edf49ccd04: Pull complete
5571a198d5e5: Pull complete
12965aa2aa24: Pull complete
cd5c00a0e311: Pull complete
5b4a21012860: Pull complete
Digest: sha256:947e1889ff53d65cd2e9dd3357d45cf8714504995564e0a7183a5ff13a605ac0
Status: Downloaded newer image for hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example:dev_latest
Creating myapp_dev_1
Attaching to myapp_dev_1
dev_1 | yarn install v0.16.1
dev_1 | success Already up-to-date.
dev_1 | Done in 0.31s.
dev_1 | npm info it worked if it ends with ok
dev_1 | npm info using npm@3.10.8
dev_1 | npm info using node@v6.9.1
dev_1 | npm info lifecycle numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT~predev: numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT
dev_1 | npm info lifecycle numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT~dev: numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT
dev_1 |
dev_1 | &gt; numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT dev /opt/app
dev_1 | &gt; concurrent --kill-others "npm run watch-client" "npm run start-dev" "npm run start-dev-api"
dev_1 |
dev_1 | Warning: "concurrent" command is deprecated, use "concurrently" instead.
dev_1 |
dev_1 | [1] npm
dev_1 | [1] info it worked if it ends with ok
dev_1 | [1] npm info using npm@3.10.8
dev_1 | [1] npm info using node@v6.9.1
dev_1 | [0] npm
dev_1 | [0]
dev_1 | [0] info
dev_1 | [0]
dev_1 | [0] it worked if it ends with
dev_1 | [0] ok
dev_1 | [0] npm
dev_1 | [0]
dev_1 | [0] info
dev_1 | [0]
dev_1 | [0] using
dev_1 | [0] npm@3.10.8
dev_1 | [0] npm
dev_1 | [0]
dev_1 | [0] info
dev_1 | [0]
dev_1 | [0] using node@v6.9.1
dev_1 | [2] npm
dev_1 | [2]
dev_1 | [2] info
dev_1 | [2]
dev_1 | [2] it worked if it ends with
dev_1 | [2] ok
dev_1 | [2] npm
dev_1 | [2]
dev_1 | [2] info
dev_1 | [2]
dev_1 | [2] using
dev_1 | [2] npm@3.10.8
dev_1 | [2] npm
dev_1 | [2]
dev_1 | [2] info
dev_1 | [2]
dev_1 | [2] using
dev_1 | [2] node@v6.9.1
dev_1 | [1] npm
dev_1 | [1]
dev_1 | [1] info lifecycle numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT~prestart-dev: numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT
dev_1 | [1] npm
dev_1 | [1]
dev_1 | [1] info
dev_1 | [1]
dev_1 | [1] lifecycle
dev_1 | [1] numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT~start-dev: numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT
dev_1 | [1]
dev_1 | [1] &gt; numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT start-dev /opt/app
dev_1 | [1] &gt; better-npm-run start-dev
dev_1 | [1]
dev_1 | [1] running better-npm-run in /opt/app
dev_1 | [1] Executing script: start-dev
dev_1 | [1]
dev_1 | [1] to be executed: node ./bin/server.js
dev_1 | [0] npm
dev_1 | [0]
dev_1 | [0] info
dev_1 | [0]
dev_1 | [0] lifecycle
dev_1 | [0] numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT~prewatch-client: numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT
dev_1 | [0] npm
dev_1 | [0]
dev_1 | [0] info
dev_1 | [0]
dev_1 | [0] lifecycle
dev_1 | [0] numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT~watch-client: numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT
dev_1 | [0]
dev_1 | [0] &gt; numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT watch-client /opt/app
dev_1 | [0] &gt; better-npm-run watch-client
dev_1 | [0]
dev_1 | [2] npm
dev_1 | [2]
dev_1 | [2] info
dev_1 | [2] lifecycle numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT~prestart-dev-api: numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT
dev_1 | [0] running better-npm-run in /opt/app
dev_1 | [2] npm
dev_1 | [2]
dev_1 | [2] info
dev_1 | [2] lifecycle
dev_1 | [2] numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT~start-dev-api: numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT
dev_1 | [2]
dev_1 | [2] &gt; numerologist-app@0.1.0-SNAPSHOT start-dev-api /opt/app
dev_1 | [2] &gt; better-npm-run start-dev-api
dev_1 | [2]
dev_1 | [0] Executing script: watch-client
dev_1 | [0]
dev_1 | [0] to be executed: node webpack/webpack-dev-server.js
dev_1 | [2] running better-npm-run in /opt/app
dev_1 | [2] Executing script: start-dev-api
dev_1 | [2]
dev_1 | [2] to be executed: node ./bin/api.js
dev_1 | [0] ==&gt; 🚧 Webpack development server listening on port 3001
dev_1 | [2] ----
dev_1 | [2] ==&gt; 🌎 API is running on port 3030
dev_1 | [2] ==&gt; 💻 Send requests to http://localhost:3030
dev_1 | [1] ----
dev_1 | [1] ==&gt; ✅ React Redux Example is running, talking to API server on 3030.
dev_1 | [1] ==&gt; 💻 Open http://0.0.0.0:3000 in a browser to view the app.
dev_1 | [0] Hash: 4bfaa3d4b9c381888d2a
dev_1 | [0] Version: webpack 1.13.3
dev_1 | [0] Time: 44424ms
dev_1 | [0] Asset Size Chunks Chunk Names
dev_1 | [0] af7ae505a9eed503f8b8e6982036873e.woff2 77.2 kB [emitted]
dev_1 | [0] f4769f9bdb7466be65088239c12046d1.eot 20.1 kB [emitted]
dev_1 | [0] fa2772327f55d8198301fdb8bcfc8158.woff 23.4 kB [emitted]
dev_1 | [0] e18bbf611f2a2e43afc071aa2f4e1512.ttf 45.4 kB [emitted]
dev_1 | [0] 89889688147bd7575d6327160d64e760.svg 109 kB [emitted]
dev_1 | [0] 674f50d287a8c48dc19ba404d20fe713.eot 166 kB [emitted]
dev_1 | [0] 448c34a56d699c29117adc64c43affeb.woff2 18 kB [emitted]
dev_1 | [0] fee66e712a8a08eef5805a46892932ad.woff 98 kB [emitted]
dev_1 | [0] b06871f281fee6b241d60582ae9369b9.ttf 166 kB [emitted]
dev_1 | [0] 912ec66d7572ff821749319396470bde.svg 444 kB [emitted]
dev_1 | [0] c29770d03d2e95e3ea5899d57c6cfeab.jpg 92.2 kB [emitted]
dev_1 | [0] main-4bfaa3d4b9c381888d2a.js 9.61 MB 0 [emitted] main
dev_1 | [0] webpack built 4bfaa3d4b9c381888d2a in 44424ms
</code></p>

<p>Then it&rsquo;s good to go, open <a href="http://localhost:3000">http://localhost:3000</a> to see the starter project home page.</p>

<p>Try to make some changes to the source code, you should see the changes reflected immediately without
any page reloading, this is called hot module reloading, a really awesome feature to boost development
productivity.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/2016/11/07/react-instant-changes.gif" title="React Project Instant Changes" ></p>

<h2>Deployment</h2>

<p>We&rsquo;re going to deploy the Docker image. There are guides that you can follow:</p>

<ul>
<li>Deploy on Heroku: <a href="https://github.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/blob/master/docs/dev-guide/how-to-deploy-on-heroku.md">https://github.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/blob/master/docs/dev-guide/how-to-deploy-on-heroku.md</a></li>
<li>Simple deployment with docker-compose: <a href="https://github.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/blob/master/docs/dev-guide/how-to-deploy-on-production-with-docker-compose.md">https://github.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/blob/master/docs/dev-guide/how-to-deploy-on-production-with-docker-compose.md</a></li>
</ul>


<p>There are many production best practices that we should improve for the starter project.</p>

<h2>CI (continuous integration) and CD (continuous delivery)</h2>

<p>By using CI and CD systems like travis-ci and gitlab-ci, we could stick to the following process:</p>

<ul>
<li>Pull request (merge request) is sent &ndash;> CI checks.</li>
<li>Code changes &ndash;> CI checks.</li>
<li>CI checking is passed, then CD starts.</li>
<li>CD will deploy automatically, for example, to Heroku or other providers or your in-house data
center.</li>
</ul>


<p>You can update all of these steps by adjusting the following files accordingly:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/blob/master/.travis.yml">https://github.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/blob/master/.travis.yml</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/blob/master/.gitlab-ci.yml">https://github.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/blob/master/.gitlab-ci.yml</a></li>
</ul>


<p>At the CI checking step, we build Docker images (both development and production images):</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/tags/">https://hub.docker.com/r/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/tags/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://gitlab.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/container_registry">https://gitlab.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/container_registry</a></li>
</ul>


<p>The development images install all development stuff (excluding the source code) so that
all the developers should have the same development environment as long as they&rsquo;re using the same
development image.</p>

<p>The production (distribution) images install and package all runtime stuff so that everyone could
run the applications right away with the same runtime environment.</p>

<p>You can see these CI systems in action:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://travis-ci.org/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/builds">https://travis-ci.org/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/builds</a></li>
<li><a href="https://gitlab.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/pipelines">https://gitlab.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example/pipelines</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Building on travis-ci is super fast and it&rsquo;s very slow on gitlab-ci. However, using gitlab is free
for unlimited projects, it includes Docker registry for free, too.</p>

<p>You can install gitlab on your server, it should be faster but you have to pay for the devops
maintenance cost.</p>

<p>If you could pay for Docker Hub, Github and Travis-CI, it&rsquo;s super fast and convenient for development
without the devops maintenance cost.</p>

<p>Or even better, ping us for consulting :&ndash;).</p>

<h2>react-boilerplate introduction</h2>

<p><code>react-redux-universal-hot-example</code> is a good start, however, there are still many improvements that
we&rsquo;d like to add, for example:</p>

<ul>
<li>Better code and component organization convention. The Angular 2 convention is a really great
inspiration for this.</li>
<li>Update dependencies to latest versions.</li>
<li>Build the deployment Docker that should include runtime stuff only, not development stuff.</li>
<li>Server side code should be production ready and optimized.</li>
</ul>


<p>And there are more to do. So we intent to create a better <code>react-redux-universal-hot-example</code> version,
we call it <code>react-boilerplate</code>.</p>

<p>The project is located at: <a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/react-boilerplate">https://github.com/teracyhq/react-boilerplate</a> . We&rsquo;ll announce v0.1.0 as soon
as possible when it&rsquo;s ready. So stay tuned! At present we should use <code>react-redux-universal-hot-example</code>.</p>

<h2>React application consulting and developing service</h2>

<p>We&rsquo;re offering React application consulting and developing service.</p>

<p>If you want React development and production deployment help, don&rsquo;t hesitate to ping us. We&rsquo;re
eager to help you to develop world-class React applications with better and better developer experience
and production deployment.</p>

<h2>Learn more</h2>

<p>You should learn more about React at:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://exploringjs.com/es6/">http://exploringjs.com/es6/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/veggiemonk/awesome-docker">https://github.com/veggiemonk/awesome-docker</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/enaqx/awesome-react">https://github.com/enaqx/awesome-react</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example#about">https://github.com/hoatle/react-redux-universal-hot-example#about</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Hopefully, this is a good start for React newbies to explore the whole new world of modern web
application development.</p>

<p>Happy hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
