<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: en | Teracy's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/categories/en/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-30T09:37:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.teracy.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Teracy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[how to make JWT requests with httpie-jwt-auth plugin?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2015/09/03/how-to-make-jwt-requests-with-httpie-jwt-auth-plugin/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-03T11:33:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2015/09/03/how-to-make-jwt-requests-with-httpie-jwt-auth-plugin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At Teracy, we embrace JWT (JSON Web Tokens)<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>  for REST APIs to make secure requests. Just for
your information: &ldquo;JSON Web Tokens are an open, industry standard RFC 7519 method for representing
claims securely between two parties&rdquo;.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>We&rsquo;re using JWT for our REST APIs basing on the flask-boilerplate<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> project that are empowering
our clients' web applications and our internal projects.</p>

<p>And to test REST APIs, we&rsquo;re using a really simple powerful http client called httpie<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> .</p>

<p>To make a JWT request with <code>httpie</code>, you need to use the following command:</p>

<p><code>
$ http example.org Authorization:'Bearer jwt_token_here'
</code></p>

<p>Hower, typing <code>Authorization</code> with the exact value format is a bit hard and error-prone, that&rsquo;s the
reason why we created <a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/httpie-jwt-auth">httpie-jwt-auth</a> plugin with the first v0.1.0 release. After installing
<code>httpie-jwt-auth</code>, you could use this instead:</p>

<p><code>
$ http --auth-type=jwt --auth=jwt_token_here: example.org
</code></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it. It&rsquo;s really easy to use for any JWT requests with <code>httpie</code>.</p>

<p>Please note that colon character at the end of <code>jwt_token_here</code>, we&rsquo;re going to work on removing
the redundant colon character with: <a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/httpie-jwt-auth/issues/3">https://github.com/teracyhq/httpie-jwt-auth/issues/3</a></p>

<p>Hope that you&rsquo;ll like it and use it as much as we do.</p>

<p>Happy developing and debugging!</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>http://jwt.io/<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>https://github.com/teracyhq/flask-boilerplate<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>https://github.com/jkbrzt/httpie<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teracy happy birthday Slack bot]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2015/07/22/teracy-birthday-slack-bot/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-22T09:19:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2015/07/22/teracy-birthday-slack-bot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2015/07/22/teracy_birthday_slack_bot.png" title="Teracy happy birthday Slack bot" ></p>

<p>Getting everything automated is one of my daily tasks, such as running tests automatically each time
there is a new commit, packaging products and sending them to customers, or deploying the
staging/ production servers when a project manager releases a new version, and more.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Today my task is something quite different: Congrats team members on their birthdays automatically
by the data got from Google calendar. After a little search, there are many automation solutions to
do it: from commercial Zapier, IFFT to opensource like Huginn.
I want something simple to use, maintenance-free, and free for small usage, so my last
choice is Zapier. It has already had the recipe<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> to read events from Google calendar and another
action to interactive with Slack that will be easy to start (although the document of the recipe
is not quite clear for a new user like me). Here is the recipe for Zapier:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/2015/07/22/Zapier_recipe_config.png" title="Zapier recipe config" ></p>

<p>With this recipe, Zapier will notify to the #_general slack channel with the message got from the
calendar description at the time of the event start. To make thing more interesting, I want to
attach a birthday cake image which has an employee name on it along with the message so I use PHP GD
to show a dynamic birthday cake taking the employee name from the calendar title and add it to the
image. It took me 30 minutes to get the birthday cake image which has space for the text, choose a
font and add it to my script. Finally, uploading it to our server and here is the result:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/2015/07/22/cake_sample.png" title="Birthday cake" ></p>

<p>This PHP script<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> along with the Zapier recipe above makes the birthday reminder more interesting.
What I&rsquo;m thinking now is some funny fortune teller texts which are added randomly to the cake, a
lucky draw game for the team members to pick up their birthday gift and hopefully some online
merchants will open their API for our script to bring the gift to our team members' homes.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>https://zapier.com/zapbook/google-calendar/slack/<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>https://github.com/teracyhq/birthday-image<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Teracy Wireframe UI kit for Sketch]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2014/12/08/free-teracy-wireframe-kit-for-sketch/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2014/12/08/free-teracy-wireframe-kit-for-sketch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2014/12/cover.jpg"></p>

<p>It’s always a good idea to begin with a wireframe when beginning a new web design or mobile app project.
Wireframes can be a big time saver as they help both designers and developers come to an agreement on placement
of major UI elements. The key is to get the layout nailed down so you don&rsquo;t have to change major layout when
 detailed design elements are in place.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>In our design process at Teracy, wireframing and mockups takes an important position. We have developed
a wireframe kit to speedup the design process and use it in our daily design workflow. Today, we are excited
 to share the version of our wireframe kit that we are using, which includes the most common UI elements
in web projects. This is the second UI kit we share to <a href="http://www.bohemiancoding.com/sketch/">Sketch</a> community, you can also check out our first freebie <a href="https://github.com/teracy-official/bootflat-ui-kit.sketch">Bootflat UI kit for Sketch</a> shared not a long time ago.</p>

<p>Here it is, hope it&rsquo;s useful for all Sketch lovers!</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/wireframe">Download the Teracy Wireframe kit for Sketch</a></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/2014/12/ss2.jpg">
<img class="center" src="/images/2014/12/ss1.jpg"></p>

<p>Features:</p>

<ul>
<li>All UI Elements are Symbols.</li>
<li>Symbols grouped by categories.</li>
<li>UI elements for mobile devices will be added in the next version.</li>
<li>Markups and annotations included.</li>
<li>Over 140 icons included.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Bootflat UI kit for Sketch]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2014/10/08/free-bootflat-ui-kit-for-sketch/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2014/10/08/free-bootflat-ui-kit-for-sketch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2014/10/cover.png"></p>

<p><strong><em>Why Sketch?</em></strong></p>

<p><a href="http://www.bohemiancoding.com/sketch/">Sketch</a> is a powerful tool designed entirely to do UI. It&rsquo;s a young graphic program when compared
to Photoshop but we see its user base&rsquo;s growing strong. Centered around vector design, Sketch is
getting plenty of buzz among UI designers as an alternative to Adobe&rsquo;s Creative Suite. With Sketch,
designs come out pixel perfect and in vector format, a requirement for multiple screen sizes.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>You may not believe how much time this application have saved us when designing UI. It&rsquo;s simple,
fast and so connected to the way designers work. You definitely should give Sketch a try in your
next project. There are already a lot of articles about how Sketch excels in designing UI. Here to
name a few:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://blog.mengto.com/sketch-vs-photoshop/">Sketch VS Photoshop</a></li>
<li><a href="http://blog.mengto.com/photoshop-users-how-to-switch-to-sketch/">Photoshop Users: How To Switch To Sketch</a></li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/@jm_denis/discovering-sketch-25545f6cb161">Discovering Sketch</a></li>
</ul>


<p><strong><em>Bootflat UI Kit</em></strong></p>

<p>At the beginning, Teracy planned to develop its own UI kit and framework based on bootstrap. It&rsquo;s a
great experience but developing and maintaining the UI kit will take time. Clock&rsquo;s still ticking.
We have to release one of our ambitious products by the end of this year.
So, we&rsquo;ve come to decide on finding an open source framework that matches our flat designs.</p>

<p>And we found <a href="http://bootflat.github.io/">Bootflat</a> &ndash; an open source Flat UI kit based on Twitter Bootstrap 3 framework. For
designers, they offer a free PSD, including a set of beautiful and pure elements, which you can
use to create startup projects, websites or iOS/Android Apps. This will save a lot of developing
time.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s still one thing that&rsquo;s bugging us though. As our company starts switching to Sketch for UI
design, this beautiful framework doesn&rsquo;t provide the .sketch file of elements, only .psd. So we
think &ldquo;OK, why not create one? Sketch community might find it helpful and it&rsquo;s also good for
creators of Bootflat.&rdquo;</p>

<p>So here it is, hope it&rsquo;s useful for Sketch lovers!</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/teracy-official/bootflat-ui-kit.sketch">Download the Bootflat UI kit for Sketch</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Team Building Activity Of Teracy In Da Nang City]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2014/09/25/first-team-building-activity-of-teracy-in-da-nang-city/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-25T10:39:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2014/09/25/first-team-building-activity-of-teracy-in-da-nang-city</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2014/09/teracy1.jpg"></p>

<p>After a hard working year, the long-awaited day had arrived &ndash; Teracy&rsquo;s vacation for 4 days and 3 nights.
This destination reaches the Central Vietnam &ndash; Da Nang, a beautiful and bustling city with the fresh
atmosphere and taste of the sea.</p>

<p>It was not simply a vacation but also a team building activity for Teracy. Although Teracy has just
come into operation with relatively few members in the North &ndash; Central &ndash; South, this trip is even
more meaningful for all Teraciers. It was the first time all the members met together to experience
moments of fun, and relaxation side by side, so everyone was very excited :)</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The journey should always have a good preparation to make sure to have a perfect trip. Just like the
other times, I encountered many difficulties and took a lot of time in preparation for the trip.</p>

<p>The most difficult thing was to find a place for travel. It seemed a simple job done, but quite hard
for me when carrying out the plan. As the members of the Teracy live in different regions of the country,
the destination must be convenient for travel, have many beautiful spots, be easy to hold team-building
activities and suitable to the budget. After careful consideration, we decided to reach Da Nang, a
Central beach full of sunshine and wind, and a young city. Da Nang is also the mid region of the
country and be able to connect the members from three Vietnamese regions of North-Central and South.</p>

<p>Next, I needed to book flight tickets for members and search for a hotel. The hotel should be center,
comfortable, but at reasonable price.</p>

<p>I also needed to find out specialties in Da Nang, what and where to eat, give the detailed schedule
for the trip.</p>

<p>Phew!  Everything was well done in the end. We were towards Da Nang together!</p>

<p><strong>4 day 3 night journey begins!</strong></p>

<p><strong>Day 1</strong></p>

<p>When walking down the airport, just at dusk, I felt the taste of the sea, fresh air, cool
peace of the city, unlike the crowded bustling scene, and hot summer in Hanoi. We
arrived at the hotel at 6.30 pm, did check-in procedures, relaxed and chatted together.
It was the first convergence of the Teraciers, (unfortunately, some members could not join) but we all
felt so familiar and close. After moments of unceasing talk, all of us felt very hungry. To the coastal
city, of course, the first dishes we chose were seafood. As planned, we tried the seafood in a pretty
cool and clean coastal restaurant. The menu had wide variety of options, all look tasty. How I could
find myself enjoy such delicious dishes in Hanoi. Until now, I still remember the fresh delicious
favor of Tamarind crab, steamed prawn and crab on that day.</p>

<p>After the meal, we walked along My Khe beach. The murmur of the wind and the waves was singing to
welcome us. A soft sea breeze kissed our face and a salty warmth blew into our face, which dissipated
all the tiredness of hard working days. The wind was still blowing and the waves were still crushing
onto our bare feet, with the cheerful voices and laugh of people.</p>

<p><strong>Day 2</strong></p>

<p>Indeed, it was an unlucky day for us. After visiting Son Tra Peninsula in the morning, we took a nap
until afternoon (I guess because we stayed up late playing cards last night). We went eating around
3 pm (well, I actually didn&rsquo;t know if it was considered as lunch or dinner). As planned, we would go
to play paint-ball after the meal. However, all of a sudden, it started to rain so we couldn&rsquo;t play.
Instead, we had to switch to go swimming when the rain was over.</p>

<p>In the evening, we went to eat veil. When telling the taxi-driver the address of a restaurant, he
said it was so hard to find that new street name so I told him to take us to another restaurant. Unluckily,
the restaurant was closed or moved to somewhere. In the end, we decided to eat &ldquo;Pork Rolls&rdquo; instead.
After that, we were eager to go to play bowling for pleasure, however, we were disheartened by seeing
the sign &ldquo;suspend operations to fix&rdquo;. Eventually, we turned to visit &ldquo;Sun-Wheel- the world&rsquo;s
fourth-largest one&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Linh Ung Pagoda &ndash; Son Tra peninsula <img class="center" src="/images/2014/09/teracy2.jpg"></p>

<p><strong>Day 3</strong></p>

<p>Fortunately, all activities took place as our schedule. In the morning, we played the
challenge game &ldquo;waterfall slide&rdquo; to challenge ourselves with rushing water, along with stones having
different sizes as obstacles to give us the sudden collision and to make the game more and more
adventurous. It was really a funny and adventurous game.</p>

<p>Prepare for sliding waterfall <img class="center" src="/images/2014/09/teracy3.jpg"></p>

<p>After that, we went to enjoy the specialties here, such as, fried brook fish, boiled chicken, stocky
wild boar meat and stir-fried wild vegetables with a little acrid, and strange taste. In the evening,
we had real comfortable moments at &ldquo;Phuong Dong&rdquo; bar. This was our second option because we were not
in proper clothes to come into &ldquo;Sky 36&rdquo;&ndash; our first option.</p>

<p>Join the exciting atmosphere at Phuong Dong bar <img class="center" src="/images/2014/09/teracy4.jpg"></p>

<p><strong>Day 4</strong></p>

<p>In the morning we went to play paint-ball game. It was a quite interesting team game. We also wore as
soldiers, looked very majestic. We had 6 people, divided into two teams. All were ready to fight!</p>

<p>Prepare for playing paint-ball game <img class="center" src="/images/2014/09/teracy5.jpg"></p>

<p>After the game, we returned to the hotel, relaxed, and checked out to visit Mr Phuong&rsquo;s house &ndash; a
colleague who lives in Da Nang. It was the last night in Da Nang, we must take advantage of the worthful
time to try other specialties of Da Nang, sat drinking coffee, and looking at the peaceful night
city.</p>

<p>The next morning, everyone got up early, packed up, went out for buying gifts for relatives and friends,
and then went to the airport. Good bye Da Nang and colleagues who live in Da Nang and Saigon!
Return to Hanoi after this trip, I miss Da Nang and my colleagues very much, miss the moments
with Teracier together, miss the murmur of sea waves, white and smooth sands,
the salty sea breeze, the memory of the pure and pristine morning, especially miss the people and the
specialties of Da Nang.</p>

<p>The trip was not as successful as expected, but it helped the members of Teracy become close and
understand each other better. It really brought us the great moments.</p>

<p>See all Tereciers next year &ndash; in the second team building activity of Teracy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
