<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: bootflat | Teracy's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/tags/bootflat/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-24T04:17:58+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.teracy.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Teracy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Bootflat UI kit for Sketch]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2014/10/08/free-bootflat-ui-kit-for-sketch/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2014/10/08/free-bootflat-ui-kit-for-sketch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2014/10/cover.png"></p>

<p><strong><em>Why Sketch?</em></strong></p>

<p><a href="http://www.bohemiancoding.com/sketch/">Sketch</a> is a powerful tool designed entirely to do UI. It&rsquo;s a young graphic program when compared
to Photoshop but we see its user base&rsquo;s growing strong. Centered around vector design, Sketch is
getting plenty of buzz among UI designers as an alternative to Adobe&rsquo;s Creative Suite. With Sketch,
designs come out pixel perfect and in vector format, a requirement for multiple screen sizes.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>You may not believe how much time this application have saved us when designing UI. It&rsquo;s simple,
fast and so connected to the way designers work. You definitely should give Sketch a try in your
next project. There are already a lot of articles about how Sketch excels in designing UI. Here to
name a few:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://blog.mengto.com/sketch-vs-photoshop/">Sketch VS Photoshop</a></li>
<li><a href="http://blog.mengto.com/photoshop-users-how-to-switch-to-sketch/">Photoshop Users: How To Switch To Sketch</a></li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/@jm_denis/discovering-sketch-25545f6cb161">Discovering Sketch</a></li>
</ul>


<p><strong><em>Bootflat UI Kit</em></strong></p>

<p>At the beginning, Teracy planned to develop its own UI kit and framework based on bootstrap. It&rsquo;s a
great experience but developing and maintaining the UI kit will take time. Clock&rsquo;s still ticking.
We have to release one of our ambitious products by the end of this year.
So, we&rsquo;ve come to decide on finding an open source framework that matches our flat designs.</p>

<p>And we found <a href="http://bootflat.github.io/">Bootflat</a> &ndash; an open source Flat UI kit based on Twitter Bootstrap 3 framework. For
designers, they offer a free PSD, including a set of beautiful and pure elements, which you can
use to create startup projects, websites or iOS/Android Apps. This will save a lot of developing
time.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s still one thing that&rsquo;s bugging us though. As our company starts switching to Sketch for UI
design, this beautiful framework doesn&rsquo;t provide the .sketch file of elements, only .psd. So we
think &ldquo;OK, why not create one? Sketch community might find it helpful and it&rsquo;s also good for
creators of Bootflat.&rdquo;</p>

<p>So here it is, hope it&rsquo;s useful for Sketch lovers!</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/teracy-official/bootflat-ui-kit.sketch">Download the Bootflat UI kit for Sketch</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
