<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: docker | Teracy's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/tags/docker/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-09-03T13:37:50+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.teracy.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Teracy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[teracy-dev v0.3.0 release]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2014/07/17/teracy-dev-v0-3-0-release/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-17T03:39:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2014/07/17/teracy-dev-v0-3-0-release</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2014/07/binary_code.jpg"></p>

<p>Creating an isolated consistent development with a predefined consistent workflow is always our
goal of development, that is the reason why we create <a href="https://github.com/teracy-official/dev">teracy-dev</a>. It is a virtualbox virtual
machine (VM) that is provisioned by <code>Chef</code><sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> and managed by <code>vagrant</code><sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>. Today, we are very happy
to announce <a href="https://github.com/teracy-official/dev">teracy-dev</a> v0.3.0 released  after more than a year of development and usage.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>We have used <code>vagrant</code> and <code>Chef</code> to provision a common VM for all our developers.
It saves a lot of time and is a very cheap operation to destroy and provision a new VM again in minutes
with the exactly defined provisioned software packages.</p>

<p>We are now using <code>Chef</code> to provision a VM with <code>nodejs</code>, <code>mysql</code>, <code>php</code>, <code>coldfusion</code> for a client to
develop a wordpress, a coldfusion and a MVC client (using backone.js with Grunt build), and it works
great.</p>

<p>Normally, it takes several days for new developers to install every packages on
their machines and they must follow instruction guide, but not anymore with <a href="https://github.com/teracy-official/dev">teracy-dev</a>.
Every new developer just needs 2-3 hours to get the dev VM provisoned for the first time (to
download the basebox thanks to <code>vagrant cloud</code>) and it just takes less than 1 minute to
<code>$ vagrant destroy</code> and <code>$ vagrant up</code> later again &ndash; this is a very cheap operation.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/teracy-official/dev">teracy-dev</a> is really a general-purpose development environment for all developers for all platforms
(<code>nodejs</code>, <code>python</code>, <code>java</code>, <code>php</code>, <code>mysql</code>, <code>posgreSQL</code>, <code>mongodb</code>) built-in and you could extend
more by using <code>Chef</code> to create more cookbooks or recipes for it.</p>

<p>However, we still have performance problem with shared folders. It is still quite slow and
painful on Windows host machine. We are going to fix this problem on the next version (v0.4.0).</p>

<p><code>docker</code><sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> is very promising and we&rsquo;d like to use it for our workflow at v0.4.0, too.</p>

<p>Please stay tuned for our upcoming exciting release version.</p>

<p>Have a nice day and happy coding!</p>

<h2>Credit</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.superbwallpapers.com/computers/binary-code-9004/">http://www.superbwallpapers.com/computers/binary-code-9004/</a></li>
</ul>

<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>http://www.getchef.com/<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>http://www.vagrantup.com/<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>https://www.docker.com/<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
