<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: cookbook | Teracy's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/tags/cookbook/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-08-27T02:32:49+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.teracy.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Teracy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[kubernetes-stack v0.1.0 Release]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2017/08/26/kubernetes-stack-v0-1-0-release/"/>
    <updated>2017-08-26T09:03:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2017/08/26/kubernetes-stack-v0-1-0-release</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been more than two months since we introduced the inception of the <code>kubernetes-stack</code> cookbook
from the blog post <a href="/2017/06/15/how-to-extend-teracy-dev-to-work-with-kubernetes/">How to extend teracy-dev to work with Kubernetes</a> and today we&rsquo;re
very happy to announce its very first milestone release.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>What&rsquo;s new?</h2>

<p>This milestone release helps us to manage the installation of these packages: <code>kubectl</code>, <code>helm</code>,
and <code>gcloud</code> automatically.</p>

<p>These are the client packages which are used to communicate and to work with the Google Cloud Platform,
Google Container Engine or any other Kubenertes servers.</p>

<p>You can install, remove any valid versions of those packages onto Ubuntu or CentOS platforms and more
supported platforms will come.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s next?</h2>

<p>This cookbook is designed to provide utilities for us to work with <code>Kubernetes</code> stack, so the next
milestone will introduce <code>kubernetes</code> resource to set up and install <code>Kubernetes</code> server which
should work the same as <code>Minukube</code> with better developer productivity enhancement. This
will allow our developers to have a quick local deployment test with k8s on their workstations.</p>

<p>By using this, we can save a lot of server cost, reduce testing time and speed up delivery time of
application deployment.</p>

<p>Developers will understand <code>Kubernetes</code> more deeply when they can do whatever they want with it.
It&rsquo;s very safe! They can destroy and set up a new deployment anytime they want without causing any
harm to their co-workers.</p>

<p>You should check out how it should be used with <code>teracy-dev</code> at <a href="https://github.com/acme101/dev-setup/blob/develop/chef/main-cookbooks/acme/recipes/k8s.rb">https://github.com/acme101/dev-setup/blob/develop/chef/main-cookbooks/acme/recipes/k8s.rb</a></p>

<p>I hope that this free cookbook could make your lives easier when working with <code>Kubernetes</code>:
<a href="https://supermarket.chef.io/cookbooks/kubernetes-stack">https://supermarket.chef.io/cookbooks/kubernetes-stack</a></p>

<p>Happy hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
