<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: news | Teracy's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-10-19T04:12:43+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.teracy.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Teracy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[flask-classful v0.14.0]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2017/10/18/flask-classful-v0-14-0/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-18T04:56:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2017/10/18/flask-classful-v0-14-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><code>Flask-Classful</code> v0.14.0 is the most significant release version since we decided to fork <code>Flask-Classy</code>
in August 2015 to continue the project development. To be honest, this release also has the most
community contribution yet. I&rsquo;d like to take this opportunity to thank everyone involved, without
your support and contribution, releasing this version is impossible.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Community support</h2>

<p>Thank you <a href="https://github.com/apiguy/">@apiguy</a> for creating such a beautiful library.</p>

<p>Thank you, everyone who contributed to the project since the fork:</p>

<p><code>
$ git log 48b7b030f16506e6eea9e217f5aa004b2cf2472f.. --format="%aN &lt;%aE&gt;" --reverse | sort | uniq
Andrew Roberts &lt;adroberts@...&gt;
Chris McNabb &lt;raizyr@...&gt;
Eli Gundry &lt;eligundry@...&gt;
Freedom Dumlao &lt;freedomdumlao@...&gt;
Hayden Chudy &lt;hjc1710@...&gt;
Hoat Le &lt;hoatle@...&gt;
Matt Billenstein &lt;matt@...&gt;
Nick Phillips &lt;nsphilli@...&gt;
Niklas B &lt;niklas@...&gt;
Stephane Rufer &lt;stephane.rufer@...&gt;
blurrcat &lt;blurrcat@...&gt;
hieptq &lt;hieptq8888@...&gt;
slhawkins &lt;slhawkins@...&gt;
</code></p>

<p>And thank you <a href="https://github.com/hjc">@hjc</a> for your helpful feedbacks and accepting
the committer invitation. I hope that we will have more and more committers like you to join the
project.</p>

<p>Thank you to everyone who has been using the library for your everyday projects, creating issues and
feedbacks to make the library better.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s new?</h2>

<p>So what&rsquo;s new with this release?</p>

<p>We have released <code>Flask-Classful</code> v0.6.11, v0.7.0, v0.7.1, v0.8.0, v0.9.0, v0.10.0, v0.11.0, v0.12.0,
v0.13.0, v0.13.1 since the fork, but mostly for bug fixes and small improvements.</p>

<p>v0.14.0 introduces a lot of exciting changes that you&rsquo;d love to use it right away. These are some of
the most exciting changes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Type hints support for py3</li>
<li><code>base_class</code> introduced</li>
<li>Add options passing to <code>werkzeug.Routing.Rule</code> from register function</li>
<li>Enable using custom decorators in FlaskView</li>
<li>Should allow specifying excluded methods from becoming routes</li>
<li>Better representations</li>
<li>Docker workflow along with teracy-dev for better dev setup</li>
</ul>


<p>You should check out the changelog and the docs for more detailed information:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Changelog: <a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/flask-classful/blob/develop/CHANGELOG.md#2017-10-05-hoat-le-hoatleteracycom">https://github.com/teracyhq/flask-classful/blob/develop/CHANGELOG.md#2017-10-05-hoat-le-hoatleteracycom</a></p></li>
<li><p>Docs: <a href="http://flask-classful.teracy.org/">http://flask-classful.teracy.org/</a></p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Lessons learned?</h2>

<p>We released v0.14.0 without breaking changes notice and migration docs which hurt our users
from upgrading. From now on, we will avoid introducing breaking changes but should add deprecated
warnings before breaking things for the next version releases.</p>

<p>v0.14.1 is on its way to fix this problem by updating the changelog and docs.</p>

<p>So rest assured and enjoy the release :&ndash;).</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s next?</h2>

<p>We created a roadmap release for v0.15.0 and we&rsquo;re waiting for the community feedbacks and ideas for
it.</p>

<p>We will add more sample projects, some projects with integration with other
popular libraries to create top-notch REST APIs. If you have such projects to be promoted,
please let us know then.</p>

<p>Enjoy and happy hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[kubernetes-stack v0.1.0 Release]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2017/08/26/kubernetes-stack-v0-1-0-release/"/>
    <updated>2017-08-26T09:03:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2017/08/26/kubernetes-stack-v0-1-0-release</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been more than two months since we introduced the inception of the <code>kubernetes-stack</code> cookbook
from the blog post <a href="/2017/06/15/how-to-extend-teracy-dev-to-work-with-kubernetes/">How to extend teracy-dev to work with Kubernetes</a> and today we&rsquo;re
very happy to announce its very first milestone release.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>What&rsquo;s new?</h2>

<p>This milestone release helps us to manage the installation of these packages: <code>kubectl</code>, <code>helm</code>,
and <code>gcloud</code> automatically.</p>

<p>These are the client packages which are used to communicate and to work with the Google Cloud Platform,
Google Container Engine or any other Kubenertes servers.</p>

<p>You can install, remove any valid versions of those packages onto Ubuntu or CentOS platforms and more
supported platforms will come.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s next?</h2>

<p>This cookbook is designed to provide utilities for us to work with <code>Kubernetes</code> stack, so the next
milestone will introduce <code>kubernetes</code> resource to set up and install <code>Kubernetes</code> server which
should work the same as <code>Minukube</code> with better developer productivity enhancement. This
will allow our developers to have a quick local deployment test with k8s on their workstations.</p>

<p>By using this, we can save a lot of server cost, reduce testing time and speed up delivery time of
application deployment.</p>

<p>Developers will understand <code>Kubernetes</code> more deeply when they can do whatever they want with it.
It&rsquo;s very safe! They can destroy and set up a new deployment anytime they want without causing any
harm to their co-workers.</p>

<p>You should check out how it should be used with <code>teracy-dev</code> at <a href="https://github.com/acme101/dev-setup/blob/develop/chef/main-cookbooks/acme/recipes/k8s.rb">https://github.com/acme101/dev-setup/blob/develop/chef/main-cookbooks/acme/recipes/k8s.rb</a></p>

<p>I hope that this free cookbook could make your lives easier when working with <code>Kubernetes</code>:
<a href="https://supermarket.chef.io/cookbooks/kubernetes-stack">https://supermarket.chef.io/cookbooks/kubernetes-stack</a></p>

<p>Happy hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[teracy-dev v0.5.0-c1 release]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2017/07/27/teracy-dev-v0-5-0-c1-release/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-27T03:41:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2017/07/27/teracy-dev-v0-5-0-c1-release</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re very happy to announce the release of teracy-dev v0.5.0-c1. This version introduces lots of features and changes which support more development, deployment stack along with Docker and Kubernetes.</p>

<h2>v0.5.0-c1</h2>

<p>As you&rsquo;ve known, the RC-1 version means “all minor bugs are fixed, the software works stably, and the code will be released unless there is a last minute bug found after test campaigns.”. However, to meet some requests from our clients and community, we added some features to this release.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Changes</h2>

<p>This major release includes some bugs fixed, document improvement and new features:</p>

<ul>
<li>Support the project base configuration. From now, you can add a list of vagrant configuration to your JSON file and extend the configuration from that.</li>
<li>Update the document for the getting started with windows environment, nodejs debugging.</li>
<li>Add many tools to help your development process.</li>
<li>Add the ability to extend and uniquely extend the array list in the JSON configuration file.</li>
<li>Introduce ACME101 as the sample project which shows the best practices of using teracy-dev.</li>
</ul>


<p>There are more that you should explore yourselves when using <code>teracy-dev</code> for a while.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s next?</h2>

<p>Along with the project base configuration we also introduce <a href="https://github.com/acme101">ACME101</a> which has many development stacks to use with teracy-dev. Hopefully, it will be useful for you and we&rsquo;re welcome any contribution, suggestion for ACME101. We&rsquo;re also adding more documents and guide for the project.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll take all the feedbacks from v0.5.0 usage to continue making <code>teracy-dev</code> better and greater.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t hesitate to use <a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/dev">teracy-dev v0.5.0-c1</a> for your everyday
projects from today by getting started with <a href="http://dev.teracy.org/docs/getting_started.html">http://dev.teracy.org/docs/getting_started.html</a></p>

<p>If you have any feedbacks or problems, you&rsquo;re welcome to create issues for the project at
<a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/dev/issues">https://github.com/teracyhq/dev/issues</a></p>

<p>Enjoy and happy hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming event: Productive development environment with teracy-dev]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2017/02/17/upcoming-event-productive-development-environment-with-teracy-dev/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-17T09:41:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2017/02/17/upcoming-event-productive-development-environment-with-teracy-dev</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2017/02/17/opentour01-productive-development-environment-teracy-dev.jpg" title="Productive development environment with teracy-dev" ></p>

<p>We are very excited about an upcoming event with the topic &ldquo;Productive development environment with teracy-dev&rdquo;
presented by Hoat Le, Co-founder, and CEO of Teracy. The event will be held on Thursday, February
23 at 6:30 PM &ndash; 9:30 PM at Toong Hoang Dao Thuy (25T2 Hoang Dao Thuy, Ha Noi). This is
the first event in the series of OpenTour&rsquo;s activities.</p>

<p>OpenTour is started from the idea of ​​collaboration, and help each other of three open source communities in
Vietnam, including OpenCPS, Vietnam OpenStack, and Docker Hanoi. OpenTour is a series of activities
and events aiming at building Vietnamese FOSS ecosystem, building a network of FOSS experts to promote
the use, application and development of FOSS in Vietnam, especially for ​​ICT enterprises
and training institutions, on the base of absorbing ideas and activity patterns of the FOSS community
in the world, and through shared activities and promoting.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><strong>Agenda</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Introduce about OpenTour</p></li>
<li><p>teracy-dev: <a href="/2016/12/20/teracy-dev-the-only-truly-universal-productive-development-platform-with-docker-on-macos-linux-and-windows/">the only truly universal productive development platform with Docker on macOS, Linux, and Windows for developers</a>.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Introduce about teracy-dev</p></li>
<li><p>The existing problems that many developers are struggling:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>The problems when there was no Docker yet</p></li>
<li><p>The problems when there was no teracy-dev yet</p></li>
<li><p>The approaches and solutions for these problems with teracy-dev</p></li>
<li><p>The 4-year story of teracy-dev</p></li>
<li><p>The Docker workflow with teracy-dev</p></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>teracy-dev demo with the real projects</p></li>
<li><p>Questions and Answers</p></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Join us! To have more details and register to join the event, please see the details at <a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/979555312146106/.">https://www.facebook.com/events/979555312146106/.</a>
It&rsquo;s our honor to have your presence at this event. See you there!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[teracy-dev v0.5.0-b1 release]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2017/02/14/teracy-dev-v0-5-0-b1-release/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-14T12:41:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2017/02/14/teracy-dev-v0-5-0-b1-release</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;re very happy to announce our so long awaiting major release of teracy-dev, the v0.5.0-b1 release
that introduces lots of features and changes, high performance with Docker workflow as the default.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>v0.5.0-b1</h2>

<p>This is the beta 1 release of v0.5.0, what does it mean? By following the
<a href="http://dev.teracy.org/docs/semantic_versioning.html">semantic versioning guide</a>, it means:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>features completed, only minor bugs are expected. Avoid refactoring here, just fix bugs</p></blockquote></p>

<p>This v0.5.0-b1 release is tested with all our projects and our clients' projects, so we can guarantee
that the release has a very high quality and stability that you can use it for everyday projects.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re still lacking lots of documentation guides for users to explore and leverage all the supported
features more easily.</p>

<h2>Changes</h2>

<p>This major release includes lots of features and improvements:</p>

<ul>
<li>high performance on Windows, especially file syncing</li>
<li>Docker workflow out of the box, can use any versions of docker, docker-compose</li>
<li>support all type of provisioners configurations</li>
<li>use public_network by default</li>
<li>config override the object within array</li>
<li>Vagrantfile-ext support</li>
<li>use rsync as the default sync mechanism (with the support from vagrant-gatling-rsync and
vagrant-rsync-back plugins)</li>
<li>reverse proxy support with /etc/hosts update for auto domain management</li>
<li>auto vagrant plugins installation support</li>
</ul>


<p>There are more that you should explore yourselves when using <code>teracy-dev</code> for a while.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s next?</h2>

<p>We&rsquo;re working hard to add more documentations and guides. We&rsquo;ll fix bugs if any.</p>

<p>After v0.5.0 final is release, we&rsquo;ll take on the next major release v0.6.0 that follow our
<a href="/2016/08/19/teracy-dev-vision/">teracy-dev&rsquo;s vision</a>:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>teracy-dev is the best universal development tool for everyone.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll take all the feedback from v0.5.0 usage to continue making <code>teracy-dev</code> better and greater.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t hesitate to use <a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/dev">teracy-dev v0.5.0-b1</a> for your everyday
projects from today by getting started with <a href="http://dev.teracy.org/docs/getting_started.html">http://dev.teracy.org/docs/getting_started.html</a></p>

<p>If you have any feedbacks or problems, you&rsquo;re welcome to create issues for the project at
<a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/dev/issues">https://github.com/teracyhq/dev/issues</a></p>

<p>Enjoy and happy hacking!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
