<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: news | Teracy's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-10-04T08:18:14+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.teracy.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Teracy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[teracy-dev v0.4.0 release]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2015/05/22/teracy-dev-v0-4-0-release/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-22T09:19:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2015/05/22/teracy-dev-v0-4-0-release</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>About 1 year 8 months ago we announced the <code>teracy-chef</code> v1.0.0 release<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> with a plan to extend
it for <code>teracy-dev</code>. And today we&rsquo;re very happy to announce <code>teracy-dev</code> v4.0.0 release, a really
important release we&rsquo;ve been waiting for after nearly 2 years of development. Why is it so
important?</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Easy Setup And Time Saving</h2>

<p>Traditionally, setting up a development environment takes a lot of time to install the required
packages and it also requires skillful developers to do it. Now with <code>teracy-dev</code>, its mission
is to be an <code>all in one development environment managed by Vagrant and provisioned by Chef</code>.
It&rsquo;s easy and cheap to install the same development environment on all types of operating
systems (Linux, Mac, Windows) by just following some simple steps with a clear guide<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>.</p>

<h2>All In One Development Environment</h2>

<p>You want to work with:</p>

<ul>
<li>Python? here we go: <a href="http://dev.teracy.org/docs/0.4.0/python_dev_guide.html">http://dev.teracy.org/docs/0.4.0/python_dev_guide.html</a></li>
<li>Node.js? here we go: <a href="http://dev.teracy.org/docs/0.4.0/nodejs_dev_guide.html">http://dev.teracy.org/docs/0.4.0/nodejs_dev_guide.html</a></li>
<li>PHP? here we go: <a href="http://dev.teracy.org/docs/0.4.0/php_dev_guide.html">http://dev.teracy.org/docs/0.4.0/php_dev_guide.html</a></li>
<li>Ruby? here we go: <a href="http://dev.teracy.org/docs/0.4.0/ruby_dev_guide.html">http://dev.teracy.org/docs/0.4.0/ruby_dev_guide.html</a></li>
<li>MySQL? here we go: <a href="http://dev.teracy.org/docs/0.4.0/databases_guide.html#mysql">http://dev.teracy.org/docs/0.4.0/databases_guide.html#mysql</a></li>
<li>Git?</li>
<li>phpMyAdmin?</li>
<li>&hellip;?</li>
</ul>


<p>All these components are already available when you setup the <code>teracy-dev</code> VM.</p>

<p>If you want to have more, such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>Java</li>
<li>PostgreSQL</li>
<li>MongoDB</li>
<li>&hellip;</li>
</ul>


<p>It&rsquo;s just a few minutes to configure and enable these components to use right away.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re using <code>teracy-dev</code> everyday for all our clients' projects and our internal projects with a
wide range of technology stacks and <code>teracy-dev</code> makes our lives (trainees, QA engineers, designers,
developers) easier to collaborate.</p>

<h2>Customization</h2>

<p>You could customize <code>teracy-dev</code> by overriding the default configuration on the
<code>vagrant_config.json</code> file<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>VM customization: networks, synced folders, memory, cpus, etc.</li>
<li>Enable/ disable or use different versions of <code>Git</code>, <code>Node.js</code>, <code>Python</code>, <code>Ruby</code>, <code>Nginx</code>, <code>Apache</code>,
<code>PHP</code>, <code>MySql</code>, <code>MongoDB</code>, <code>PostgreSQL</code>, <code>Java</code>, <code>PHPMyAdmin</code>, <code>codebox</code>.</li>
</ul>


<p>If you want to have more customization, please follow:
<a href="http://dev.teracy.org/docs/0.4.0/teracy_dev_development.html">http://dev.teracy.org/docs/0.4.0/teracy_dev_development.html</a></p>

<h2>How To Upgrade</h2>

<p>We support seamless upgrade, these are the steps for upgrading if you&rsquo;re using <code>teracy-dev</code> v0.3.5:</p>

<p><code>
$ cd ~/teracy-dev
$ git pull
$ vagrant box update
</code></p>

<p><code>teracy-dev</code> v0.4.0 introduced a breaking change of configuration for the VM&rsquo;s network<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup>,
so you need to adjust it on your <code>vagrant_config_override.js</code> if you&rsquo;re overriding it.</p>

<p>Then:</p>

<p><code>
$ vagrant destroy
$ vagrant up
</code></p>

<p>And you&rsquo;re done.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s Next?</h2>

<p>We&rsquo;re going to back-port some stuff from <code>teracy-dev</code> to <code>teracy-chef</code> to make it modular so
that everyone could leverage <code>teracy-chef</code> to setup their own development environment like we&rsquo;re
doing for <code>teracy-dev</code> such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>LAMP stack only</li>
<li>Java stack only</li>
<li>Ruby stack only</li>
<li>Node.js stack only</li>
<li>Ruby stack only</li>
</ul>


<p>The possibilies are limitless for everyone to create their own baseboxes.</p>

<p>By the next versions of <code>teracy-chef</code> and <code>teracy-dev</code>, we&rsquo;ll support provisioning the servers
with <code>knife-solo</code><sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" rel="footnote">5</a></sup>.</p>

<p>And we&rsquo;ll also support many different types of operating systems for the base boxes, even with
Windows base boxes.</p>

<p>We can&rsquo;t wait to continue developing and releasing the next versions.</p>

<h2>0.4.x Releases</h2>

<p>This section will be used to announce v0.4.x releases and we&rsquo;re very happy to announce:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><code>teracy-dev</code> v0.4.1 release which fixes 2 bugs:</p>

<ul>
<li>[DEV-232] &ndash; mysql with php not work</li>
<li>[DEV-233] &ndash; wrong default forwarded port for mysql</li>
</ul>


<p>Details: <a href="https://issues.teracy.org/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10400&amp;version=12200">https://issues.teracy.org/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10400&amp;version=12200</a></p></li>
</ul>


<h2>One More Thing&hellip;</h2>

<p>If you want to get our support, consultant or to develop web applications, please drop us an
email at: hq[at]teracy.com to collaborate and get your dreams come true!</p>

<p>Or you could contact us via:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.upwork.com/companies/Teracy_~01bea4242f6b165592">https://www.upwork.com/companies/Teracy_~01bea4242f6b165592</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.upwork.com/users/~01ae32490908995384">https://www.upwork.com/users/~01ae32490908995384</a></li>
</ul>


<p>In the meantime, enjoy <code>teracy-dev</code> for all your projects and hope that you will love using it as
much as we do.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s get started: <a href="http://dev.teracy.org/docs/0.4.0/getting_started.html">http://dev.teracy.org/docs/0.4.0/getting_started.html</a></p>

<p>Happy developing!</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>http://blog.teracy.com/2013/09/23/teracy-chef-v0-1-0-release/<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>http://dev.teracy.org/docs/getting_started.html<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>https://github.com/teracyhq/dev/blob/v0.4.0/vagrant_config.json<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>https://issues.teracy.org/browse/DEV-198<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>http://matschaffer.github.io/knife-solo/<a href="#fnref:5" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Teracy Wireframe UI kit for Sketch]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2014/12/08/free-teracy-wireframe-kit-for-sketch/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2014/12/08/free-teracy-wireframe-kit-for-sketch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2014/12/cover.jpg"></p>

<p>It’s always a good idea to begin with a wireframe when beginning a new web design or mobile app project.
Wireframes can be a big time saver as they help both designers and developers come to an agreement on placement
of major UI elements. The key is to get the layout nailed down so you don&rsquo;t have to change major layout when
 detailed design elements are in place.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>In our design process at Teracy, wireframing and mockups takes an important position. We have developed
a wireframe kit to speedup the design process and use it in our daily design workflow. Today, we are excited
 to share the version of our wireframe kit that we are using, which includes the most common UI elements
in web projects. This is the second UI kit we share to <a href="http://www.bohemiancoding.com/sketch/">Sketch</a> community, you can also check out our first freebie <a href="https://github.com/teracy-official/bootflat-ui-kit.sketch">Bootflat UI kit for Sketch</a> shared not a long time ago.</p>

<p>Here it is, hope it&rsquo;s useful for all Sketch lovers!</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/wireframe">Download the Teracy Wireframe kit for Sketch</a></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/2014/12/ss2.jpg">
<img class="center" src="/images/2014/12/ss1.jpg"></p>

<p>Features:</p>

<ul>
<li>All UI Elements are Symbols.</li>
<li>Symbols grouped by categories.</li>
<li>UI elements for mobile devices will be added in the next version.</li>
<li>Markups and annotations included.</li>
<li>Over 140 icons included.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Bootflat UI kit for Sketch]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2014/10/08/free-bootflat-ui-kit-for-sketch/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2014/10/08/free-bootflat-ui-kit-for-sketch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2014/10/cover.png"></p>

<p><strong><em>Why Sketch?</em></strong></p>

<p><a href="http://www.bohemiancoding.com/sketch/">Sketch</a> is a powerful tool designed entirely to do UI. It&rsquo;s a young graphic program when compared
to Photoshop but we see its user base&rsquo;s growing strong. Centered around vector design, Sketch is
getting plenty of buzz among UI designers as an alternative to Adobe&rsquo;s Creative Suite. With Sketch,
designs come out pixel perfect and in vector format, a requirement for multiple screen sizes.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>You may not believe how much time this application have saved us when designing UI. It&rsquo;s simple,
fast and so connected to the way designers work. You definitely should give Sketch a try in your
next project. There are already a lot of articles about how Sketch excels in designing UI. Here to
name a few:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://blog.mengto.com/sketch-vs-photoshop/">Sketch VS Photoshop</a></li>
<li><a href="http://blog.mengto.com/photoshop-users-how-to-switch-to-sketch/">Photoshop Users: How To Switch To Sketch</a></li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/@jm_denis/discovering-sketch-25545f6cb161">Discovering Sketch</a></li>
</ul>


<p><strong><em>Bootflat UI Kit</em></strong></p>

<p>At the beginning, Teracy planned to develop its own UI kit and framework based on bootstrap. It&rsquo;s a
great experience but developing and maintaining the UI kit will take time. Clock&rsquo;s still ticking.
We have to release one of our ambitious products by the end of this year.
So, we&rsquo;ve come to decide on finding an open source framework that matches our flat designs.</p>

<p>And we found <a href="http://bootflat.github.io/">Bootflat</a> &ndash; an open source Flat UI kit based on Twitter Bootstrap 3 framework. For
designers, they offer a free PSD, including a set of beautiful and pure elements, which you can
use to create startup projects, websites or iOS/Android Apps. This will save a lot of developing
time.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s still one thing that&rsquo;s bugging us though. As our company starts switching to Sketch for UI
design, this beautiful framework doesn&rsquo;t provide the .sketch file of elements, only .psd. So we
think &ldquo;OK, why not create one? Sketch community might find it helpful and it&rsquo;s also good for
creators of Bootflat.&rdquo;</p>

<p>So here it is, hope it&rsquo;s useful for Sketch lovers!</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/teracy-official/bootflat-ui-kit.sketch">Download the Bootflat UI kit for Sketch</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Team Building Activity Of Teracy In Da Nang City]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2014/09/25/first-team-building-activity-of-teracy-in-da-nang-city/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-25T10:39:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2014/09/25/first-team-building-activity-of-teracy-in-da-nang-city</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2014/09/teracy1.jpg"></p>

<p>After a hard working year, the long-awaited day had arrived &ndash; Teracy&rsquo;s vacation for 4 days and 3 nights.
This destination reaches the Central Vietnam &ndash; Da Nang, a beautiful and bustling city with the fresh
atmosphere and taste of the sea.</p>

<p>It was not simply a vacation but also a team building activity for Teracy. Although Teracy has just
come into operation with relatively few members in the North &ndash; Central &ndash; South, this trip is even
more meaningful for all Teraciers. It was the first time all the members met together to experience
moments of fun, and relaxation side by side, so everyone was very excited :)</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The journey should always have a good preparation to make sure to have a perfect trip. Just like the
other times, I encountered many difficulties and took a lot of time in preparation for the trip.</p>

<p>The most difficult thing was to find a place for travel. It seemed a simple job done, but quite hard
for me when carrying out the plan. As the members of the Teracy live in different regions of the country,
the destination must be convenient for travel, have many beautiful spots, be easy to hold team-building
activities and suitable to the budget. After careful consideration, we decided to reach Da Nang, a
Central beach full of sunshine and wind, and a young city. Da Nang is also the mid region of the
country and be able to connect the members from three Vietnamese regions of North-Central and South.</p>

<p>Next, I needed to book flight tickets for members and search for a hotel. The hotel should be center,
comfortable, but at reasonable price.</p>

<p>I also needed to find out specialties in Da Nang, what and where to eat, give the detailed schedule
for the trip.</p>

<p>Phew!  Everything was well done in the end. We were towards Da Nang together!</p>

<p><strong>4 day 3 night journey begins!</strong></p>

<p><strong>Day 1</strong></p>

<p>When walking down the airport, just at dusk, I felt the taste of the sea, fresh air, cool
peace of the city, unlike the crowded bustling scene, and hot summer in Hanoi. We
arrived at the hotel at 6.30 pm, did check-in procedures, relaxed and chatted together.
It was the first convergence of the Teraciers, (unfortunately, some members could not join) but we all
felt so familiar and close. After moments of unceasing talk, all of us felt very hungry. To the coastal
city, of course, the first dishes we chose were seafood. As planned, we tried the seafood in a pretty
cool and clean coastal restaurant. The menu had wide variety of options, all look tasty. How I could
find myself enjoy such delicious dishes in Hanoi. Until now, I still remember the fresh delicious
favor of Tamarind crab, steamed prawn and crab on that day.</p>

<p>After the meal, we walked along My Khe beach. The murmur of the wind and the waves was singing to
welcome us. A soft sea breeze kissed our face and a salty warmth blew into our face, which dissipated
all the tiredness of hard working days. The wind was still blowing and the waves were still crushing
onto our bare feet, with the cheerful voices and laugh of people.</p>

<p><strong>Day 2</strong></p>

<p>Indeed, it was an unlucky day for us. After visiting Son Tra Peninsula in the morning, we took a nap
until afternoon (I guess because we stayed up late playing cards last night). We went eating around
3 pm (well, I actually didn&rsquo;t know if it was considered as lunch or dinner). As planned, we would go
to play paint-ball after the meal. However, all of a sudden, it started to rain so we couldn&rsquo;t play.
Instead, we had to switch to go swimming when the rain was over.</p>

<p>In the evening, we went to eat veil. When telling the taxi-driver the address of a restaurant, he
said it was so hard to find that new street name so I told him to take us to another restaurant. Unluckily,
the restaurant was closed or moved to somewhere. In the end, we decided to eat &ldquo;Pork Rolls&rdquo; instead.
After that, we were eager to go to play bowling for pleasure, however, we were disheartened by seeing
the sign &ldquo;suspend operations to fix&rdquo;. Eventually, we turned to visit &ldquo;Sun-Wheel- the world&rsquo;s
fourth-largest one&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Linh Ung Pagoda &ndash; Son Tra peninsula <img class="center" src="/images/2014/09/teracy2.jpg"></p>

<p><strong>Day 3</strong></p>

<p>Fortunately, all activities took place as our schedule. In the morning, we played the
challenge game &ldquo;waterfall slide&rdquo; to challenge ourselves with rushing water, along with stones having
different sizes as obstacles to give us the sudden collision and to make the game more and more
adventurous. It was really a funny and adventurous game.</p>

<p>Prepare for sliding waterfall <img class="center" src="/images/2014/09/teracy3.jpg"></p>

<p>After that, we went to enjoy the specialties here, such as, fried brook fish, boiled chicken, stocky
wild boar meat and stir-fried wild vegetables with a little acrid, and strange taste. In the evening,
we had real comfortable moments at &ldquo;Phuong Dong&rdquo; bar. This was our second option because we were not
in proper clothes to come into &ldquo;Sky 36&rdquo;&ndash; our first option.</p>

<p>Join the exciting atmosphere at Phuong Dong bar <img class="center" src="/images/2014/09/teracy4.jpg"></p>

<p><strong>Day 4</strong></p>

<p>In the morning we went to play paint-ball game. It was a quite interesting team game. We also wore as
soldiers, looked very majestic. We had 6 people, divided into two teams. All were ready to fight!</p>

<p>Prepare for playing paint-ball game <img class="center" src="/images/2014/09/teracy5.jpg"></p>

<p>After the game, we returned to the hotel, relaxed, and checked out to visit Mr Phuong&rsquo;s house &ndash; a
colleague who lives in Da Nang. It was the last night in Da Nang, we must take advantage of the worthful
time to try other specialties of Da Nang, sat drinking coffee, and looking at the peaceful night
city.</p>

<p>The next morning, everyone got up early, packed up, went out for buying gifts for relatives and friends,
and then went to the airport. Good bye Da Nang and colleagues who live in Da Nang and Saigon!
Return to Hanoi after this trip, I miss Da Nang and my colleagues very much, miss the moments
with Teracier together, miss the murmur of sea waves, white and smooth sands,
the salty sea breeze, the memory of the pure and pristine morning, especially miss the people and the
specialties of Da Nang.</p>

<p>The trip was not as successful as expected, but it helped the members of Teracy become close and
understand each other better. It really brought us the great moments.</p>

<p>See all Tereciers next year &ndash; in the second team building activity of Teracy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hoạt Động Team Building Đầu Tiên Của Teracy]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2014/09/24/hoat-dong-team-building-dau-tien-cua-teracy/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-24T15:46:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2014/09/24/hoat-dong-team-building-dau-tien-cua-teracy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2014/09/teracy1.jpg"></p>

<p>Sau một năm làm việc vất vả thì cái ngày mong đợi cũng đã đến &ndash; một chuyến nghỉ mát 4 ngày 3 đêm
cùng Teracy. Chuyến đi lần này hướng về miền trung để đến với mảnh đất Đà Nẵng – một
thành phố tươi trẻ, năng động với bầu không khí trong lành đậm hương vị của biển khơi.</p>

<p>Đây không đơn giản chỉ là một kỳ nghỉ mát, đối với Teracy thì còn là một hoạt động team building. Do
Teracy vừa mới đi vào hoạt động chưa lâu, số thành viên còn khá ít ở ba miền Bắc &ndash; Trung &ndash; Nam, nên
chuyến đi này lại càng có ý nghĩa với tất cả các Teracier. Đây là lần đầu tiên tất cả các thành viên
được gặp mặt nhau, cùng trải qua những giây phút vui chơi, nghỉ ngơi bên nhau&hellip;Vì thế mà ai cũng háo
hức lắm :)</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Hành trình nào cũng cần có sự chuẩn bị trước thật tốt để đảm bảo có một chuyến đi thật hoàn hảo. Cũng
như các hành trình khác, tôi gặp rất nhiều khó khăn và mất rất nhiều thời gian trong công tác chuẩn bị.</p>

<p>Khó khăn nhất là việc tìm điểm đến. Tưởng chừng công việc này đơn giản lắm, nhưng khi bắt tay
vào lên kế hoạch lại hoàn toàn ko đơn giản chút nào. Vì các thành viên của Teracy thì sinh sống ở
các miền khác nhau trong cả nước, do đó việc lựa chọn địa điểm làm sao phải thuận tiện cho việc
đi lại, phù hợp với ngân sách, có các hoạt động team building, có những danh lam thắng cảnh nổi
tiếng&hellip; Sau khi cân nhắc kỹ lưỡng, chúng tôi quyết định chọn Đà Nẵng, một bãi biển miền trung đầy
nắng và gió, một thành phố trẻ. Đà Nẵng cũng là điểm giữa của đất nước và có thể kết nối các thành
viên tại 3 miền Bắc Trung Nam.</p>

<p>Tiếp theo là book vé máy bay cho các thành viên và tìm kiếm khách sạn. Tiêu chí chọn khách sạn
của chúng tôi là phải thật sạch sẽ, tiện nghi, trung tâm những nơi sẽ đến thăm, giá cả hợp lý.
Tôi cũng cần tìm xem ở Đà Nẵng có những đặc sản gì, đi ăn gì, ở đâu và lên lịch trình chi tiết cho
chuyến đi nữa, cả đoàn sẽ đi thăm thắng cảnh nào, rồi sẽ chơi trò gì để tất cả mọi người đều có thể
tham gia và thấy thật sảng khoái&hellip;</p>

<p>Phù!!! cuối cùng thì mọi thứ cũng đã xong rồi. Chúng ta cùng tiến về Đà Nẵng nào!</p>

<p><strong>Hành trình 4 ngày 3 đêm bắt đầu!</strong></p>

<p><strong>Ngày đầu tiên:</strong></p>

<p>Khi bước xuống sân bay, vừa lúc chiều tối, tôi đã cảm nhận được mùi vị của
biển khơi, bầu không khí trong lành, mát mẻ, sự bình yên của thành phố, khác hẳn cảnh xô bồ đông
đúc, nóng nực của mùa hè ở chốn Hà Thành. Đúng 18h30, chúng tôi đến khách sạn, làm thủ tục
check-in, nghỉ ngơi và ngồi chuyện trò cùng tất cả các thành viên ở cả 3 miền. Lần đâu tiên hội tụ
các Teracier, (rất tiếc là chưa đông đủ) nhưng tất cả đều cảm thấy thật thân quen và gần gũi. Sau phút
giây gặp nhau chuyện trò không ngớt, những cái bụng bắt đầu sôi réo ầm ầm giục đi ăn tối rồi :).
Đến với thành phố biển, tất nhiên món ăn đầu tiên chúng tôi chọn là hải sản. Như đã lên kế hoạch
từ trước, chúng tôi vào một nhà hàng khá thoáng mát, sạch sẽ. Vừa ngồi vào bàn, một em nhân viên
phục vụ đã chạy đến niềm nở tươi cười, bảo chúng tôi gọi món. Ực! Ực! Nhìn thực đơn đã thấy ngon
lắm rồi. Ở Hà nội, làm gì kiếm được những món ngon, bổ, rẻ như thế này :) Lần lượt nào là cua rang me,
tôm hấp, ghẹ luộc&hellip;. được mang lên. Ngon quá, giờ nghĩ lại vẫn còn thèm lắm :) Sau khi ăn uống no
say rồi, cả đoàn cùng nhau đi dạo dọc bãi biển Mỹ Khê. Tiếng sóng rì rào của biển như đang ca hát
chào gọi chúng tôi. Làn gió biển mát rượi, hơi mằn mặn phả nhẹ vào mặt xua tan tất cả mệt mỏi
sau những ngày làm việc bận rộn. Gió cứ thổi, sóng cữ vỗ nhẹ vào những đôi chân trần, hòa quyện
trong tiếng cười nói vui nhộn của mọi người&hellip;.</p>

<p><strong>Ngày thứ 2:</strong></p>

<p>Quả thực đó là ngày không may mắn. Buổi sáng sau khi đi bán đảo Sơn Trà về thì
mọi người ngủ luôn đến chiều (chắc do tối qua thức khuya chơi bài), đến 15h giờ mới lục đục đi ăn
(chẳng hiểu là ăn trưa hay ăn tối nữa).Theo kế hoạch, sau khi ăn xong chúng tôi sẽ đi bắn súng sơn
nhưng bất ngờ trời lại đổ mưa nên không thể đi được (thế là kế hoạch đổ bể, đành chuyển sang đi tắm
biển). Buổi tối chúng tôi đi ăn thịt bê, khi lên taxi bảo họ chở đến địa chỉ của quán thứ nhất họ bảo
tên đường này mới nên khó tìm, đang thở phào vì có quán ăn dự phòng khác nhưng khi đến nơi thì
giật mình vì quán đã chuyển sang địa điểm khác. Chúng tôi đành chuyển sang ăn Bánh Tráng Thịt
Heo, ăn xong chúng tôi hí hửng bàn nhau đi chơi bowling để đổi gió đến nơi thì chán hẳn khi nhìn
thấy tấm biển ”tạm ngưng hoạt động để sửa chữa”. Không đổi được gió nên chúng tôi quay lại đi
“vòng quay mặt trời &ndash; vòng quay lớn thứ 4 trên thế giới”. May thay nó chưa bị đóng cửa.</p>

<p> Chùa Linh Ứng &ndash; Bán đảo Sơn Trà <img class="center" src="/images/2014/09/teracy2.jpg"></p>

<p><strong>Ngày thứ 3:</strong></p>

<p> May sao mọi hoạt động diễn ra theo đúng kế hoạch. Buổi sáng chúng tôi đi vượt
thác để thử sức mình trên những dòng nước chảy xiết, cùng với những chú đá đủ kích cỡ to nhỏ nằm
nghênh ngang giữa đường như thể làm chướng ngại vật tạo cho chúng tôi những cú hích bất ngờ
khiến trò chơi càng thêm phần mạo hiểm (trò chơi khá vui và thú vị mỗi tội sắc da có hơi chuyển
màu một chút).</p>

<p>Chuẩn bị vượt thác <img class="center" src="/images/2014/09/teracy3.jpg"></p>

<p>Chơi xong chúng tôi đi thưởng thức những đặc sản nơi đây (với món cá suối rán
giòn rụm, món gà rừng, lợn rừng thịt chắc nịch và món rau rừng xào có vị hơi chát chát khi ăn xong
còn để lại một dư vị khó tả). Buổi tối chúng tôi có những giây phút thật sự thoải mái ở bar Phương
Đông (đây là phương án 2 của chúng tôi vì không được vào bar Sky 36 do không mặc đúng trang
phục).</p>

<p>Hòa mình vào không khí sôi động tại bar Phương Đông<img class="center" src="/images/2014/09/teracy4.jpg"></p>

<p><strong>Ngày thứ 4:</strong></p>

<p>Buối sáng chúng tôi đi bắn súng sơn. Đây là trò chơi tập thể khá thú vị và còn được
mặc bộ quần áo như các chú bộ đội ấy, nhìn oai ghê cơ. Chúng tôi có 6 người, chia ra làm 2 đội. Tất
cả sẵn sàng chiến đấu nhé!</p>

<p>Sẵn sàng ra trận bắn súng sơn <img class="center" src="/images/2014/09/teracy5.jpg"></p>

<p>Sau khi &ldquo;ra trận&rdquo; về, chúng tôi trở về khách sạn, nghỉ ngơi, trả phòng rồi đến thăm nhà anh Phương &ndash;
1 đồng nghiệp đang sống ở Đà Nẵng. Còn đêm cuối cùng ở Đà Nẵng thôi, cả hội đều phải tận dụng
triệt để thời gian vàng bạc này để đi ăn các món đặc sản còn lại của Đà Nẵng và ngồi uống cafe,
ngắm thành phố đêm yên bình&hellip;</p>

<p>Sáng hôm sau mọi người đều dậy sớm, dọn đồ, tranh thủ đi mua quà cho người thân, rồi ra sân
bay. Tạm biệt Đà Nẵng nhé, tạm biệt các đồng nghiệp đang sống ở Đà Nẵng và Sài Gòn nhé. Trở về
Hà Nội sau chuyến đi này thấy nhớ Đà Nẵng ghê, nhớ các Terecier lắm, nhớ những phút giây cùng
các bạn vui cười bên nhau, nhớ tiếng sóng biển rì rầm, bờ cát trắng mìn, nhớ làn gió mằn mặn của
biển khơi, nhớ những buổi sáng trong lành tinh khôi, và đặc biệt là người dân Đà Nẵng cùng những
món ăn độc đáo nơi đây&hellip;</p>

<p>Mặc dù chuyến đi thực sự chưa thành công như mong đợi, nhưng nó đã giúp cho tập thể Teracy trở
nên thân thiết, gắn bó, hiểu nhau hơn và thêm yêu quý nhau hơn.</p>

<p>Hẹn gặp lại tất cả các Terecier năm sau nhá &ndash; trong hoạt động team building lần 2 của Teracy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
