<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: angular-boilerplate | Teracy's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/tags/angular-boilerplate/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-04-20T09:26:29+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.teracy.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Teracy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to develop Angular 2+ applications easily with Docker, angular-cli and angular-boilerplate]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2017/03/22/how-to-develop-angular-2-applications-easily-with-docker-angular-cli-and-angular-boilerplate/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-22T18:16:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2017/03/22/how-to-develop-angular-2-applications-easily-with-docker-angular-cli-and-angular-boilerplate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2017/03/22/acme101-angular-hello-world.gif" title="Acme 101 angular-hello-world" ></p>

<p>About six months ago we published
<a href="/2016/09/22/how-to-develop-angular-2-applications-easily-with-docker-and-angular-cli/">How to Develop Angular 2 Applications Easily With Docker and Angular-cli</a> which received a lot of
Angular community feedbacks and questions.</p>

<p>Six months has passed and we&rsquo;d like to share more best practices to develop Angular applications with
Docker after working on it for a while.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Received Feedbacks</h2>

<p>We received some outstanding feedbacks and questions about:</p>

<ul>
<li>Problems when running Docker images after pulling the built Docker images.</li>
<li>How to build prod Docker image and run it.</li>
<li>How to get <code>npm</code> packages into the <code>node_modules</code> to work within your IDE, editor.</li>
</ul>


<p>And in this blog post, we&rsquo;re going to solve all of them and even with more best practices.</p>

<h2>angular-boilerplate</h2>

<p>Setting up Angular projects with Docker to get it work properly is not easy. Luckily, we&rsquo;ve done
all the heavy lifting for you with the <code>angular-boilerplate</code> project.</p>

<p><code>angular-boilerplate</code> was created as a seed project that can be used to generate any new Angular
projects having Docker and CI/CD system support.</p>

<p>To generate a new Angular project, you can check out the
<a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/angular-boilerplate/blob/master/README.md">README.md</a> file to follow.</p>

<h2>angular-hello-world</h2>

<p>In this section, I&rsquo;ll introduce you the best way to set up a development environment and you can apply
it for all your projects, not just Angular projects. After some first required steps to set up
<code>acme-dev</code>, after <code>$ vagrant up</code>, you can start coding immediately, you don&rsquo;t have to learn the set
up steps at first, but defer it later.</p>

<p>Suppose that we&rsquo;re in Acme organization and we need to work on the <code>angular-hello-world</code> project.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s follow the README file here: <a href="https://github.com/acme101/angular-hello-world">https://github.com/acme101/angular-hello-world</a></p>

<p>It tells us to follow <a href="https://github.com/acme101/dev-setup/blob/master/README.md">https://github.com/acme101/dev-setup/blob/master/README.md</a></p>

<p>By setting up <code>acme-dev</code>, we can use it for all types of projects with different stacks with the same
set up workflow, it means that we can save a lot of time and effort to add more and more projects.</p>

<p>Re-using and scaling boots productivity and cost savings.</p>

<h2>Best practices</h2>

<p>By looking into the <code>angular-boilerplate</code> or <code>angular-hello-world</code>, you can see the following best
practices:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>We should build the production Docker image for production deployment.</p></li>
<li><p>We should work on dev mode on local dev.</p></li>
<li><p>We should work on prod mode on local dev.</p></li>
<li><p>We should review others' work on local dev.</p></li>
<li><p>We should use alias domains instead of fixed ports to avoid conflicts.</p></li>
<li><p>We should generate <code>node_modules</code> to work on the npm packages safely within your IDE.</p></li>
<li><p>We should use <code>yarn</code> instead <code>npm</code> as the node package manager.</p></li>
<li><p>We should test both dev and prod modes on local dev.</p></li>
<li><p>We should test both http and https modes on local dev.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>All the instruction should be updated in the README file, please follow there to apply for your
project: <a href="https://github.com/acme101/angular-hello-world/blob/develop/README.md">https://github.com/acme101/angular-hello-world/blob/develop/README.md</a></p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>All the heavy lifting and best practices are documented into the corresponding projects, that&rsquo;s how
we should do so that everyone can follow easily and we can support each other with ease, too.</p>

<p>Hopefully, this will help you a lot with your Angular projects and any other projects that you can
apply similarly.</p>

<p>Happy hacking and don&rsquo;t forget to let us know your feedbacks and questions by leaving your comments!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to develop Angular 2 applications easily with Docker and angular-cli]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teracy.com/2016/09/22/how-to-develop-angular-2-applications-easily-with-docker-and-angular-cli/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-22T12:44:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teracy.com/2016/09/22/how-to-develop-angular-2-applications-easily-with-docker-and-angular-cli</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/2016/09/22/angular-boilerplate.png" title="angular-boilerplate" ></p>

<p><strong>Note:</strong></p>

<p>This post is outdated, please follow the <a href="/2017/03/22/how-to-develop-angular-2-applications-easily-with-docker-angular-cli-and-angular-boilerplate/">How to develop Angular 2+ applications easily with Docker, angular-cli and angular-boilerplate</a>
blog post instead.</p>

<hr />

<p>Everyone who is new to Angular 2 usually has many difficulties to get started with it, even with the
getting started article from the Angular 2 official documentation. That&rsquo;s the reason why
<a href="https://cli.angular.io/">angular-cli</a> is created to ease the pain. <code>angular-cli</code> is a great CLI
tool, however, it takes a lot of time to get it working by installing nodejs and <code>angular-cli</code>.
Luckily, we&rsquo;ve created <a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/docker-angular-cli">docker-angular-cli</a> project
to build a Docker image so that anyone could use it right away for any Angular 2 projects without the
hassle of installing nodejs and <code>angular-cli</code>. This guide will help you get started in the most
easily and convenient way. It&rsquo;s assumed that you don&rsquo;t need to master Docker but only require that
Docker is installed on your machine and you could follow the instructions below.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>0. Prerequisites</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>You must set up <code>docker</code> and <code>docker-compose</code> easily with <code>teracy-dev</code> first:
<a href="/2016/12/20/teracy-dev-the-only-truly-universal-productive-development-platform-with-docker-on-macos-linux-and-windows/">teracy-dev &ndash; the only truly universal productive development platform with Docker on macOS, Linux and Windows!</a></p></li>
<li><p>After <code>teracy-dev</code> is set up, you already have <code>docker</code> and <code>docker-compose</code> installed.</p></li>
<li><p><code>docker-angular-cli</code> is tested with <code>Docker</code> v1.12.1 and <code>docker-compose</code> v1.8.0 with the native app
on Mac and on Ubuntu. It should work well on Windows, too.</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>1. Init a new project</h2>

<p>First, to init a new Angular 2 project, follow:</p>

<p><code>
$ mkdir new-ng-project
$ cd new-ng-project
$ docker run -it --rm -v "$PWD":/usr/src -w /usr/src teracy/angular-cli /bin/bash
</code></p>

<p>After that, you should be presented with bash console for the docker container. Use <code>ng init</code> to
init a new project.</p>

<p>```</p>

<h1>ng init &mdash;name &lt;project-name> &mdash;style scss</h1>

<p>```</p>

<p>You should see the &lt;project-name> yourself. By default, the style file is <code>css</code>. I recommend using
<code>scss</code> extension for style files.</p>

<h2>2. Add Dockerfile and docker-compose.yml file</h2>

<p>Add Dockerfile and docker-compose.yml as I did with <a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/angular-boilerplate/commit/082a879c5df3fa0ae6ddc000d84512754b62a642">https://github.com/teracyhq/angular-boilerplate/commit/082a879c5df3fa0ae6ddc000d84512754b62a642</a></p>

<h2>3. Note for angular-boilerplate</h2>

<p>For easier setup with best practices, you can combine the 2 steps above (1 + 2) with:</p>

<p><code>
$ git clone https://github.com/teracyhq/angular-boilerplate.git --depth=1 new-ng-project
</code></p>

<p>More useful stuff will come to <a href="https://github.com/teracyhq/angular-boilerplate">angular-boilerplate</a>
later such as CI, CD, production deployment, server side rendering, desktop app and native apps, etc
best practices.</p>

<h2>4. Serve</h2>

<p>To start serving the web app, follow:</p>

<p><code>
$ docker-compose up serve
</code></p>

<p>and then open <a href="http://localhost:4200">http://localhost:4200</a> to see the web app.</p>

<h2>5. Test</h2>

<p>To run the unit test with Karma and Chrome, follow:</p>

<p><code>
$ docker-compose up test
</code></p>

<p>and you should see the unit test running on Chrome browser pre-installed on the Docker image.</p>

<h2>6. Exec commands</h2>

<p>To exec some commands, for example:</p>

<p>for linting (code style checking):</p>

<p><code>
$ docker-compose exec serve ng lint
</code></p>

<p>or for installing more npm packages:</p>

<p><code>
$ docker-compose exec serve npm install
</code></p>

<p>or for running unit tests:</p>

<p><code>
$ docker-compose exec serve ng test --browsers Chrome_no_sandbox
</code></p>

<p>You can exec any commands on the running container.</p>

<h2>7. Develop</h2>

<p>Or if you want to open a new ssh session, open a new terminal window, and execute this:</p>

<p><code>
$ cd new-ng-project
$ docker-compose run serve /bin/bash
</code></p>

<p>and then you should see something like:</p>

<p><code>
Starting virtual X frame buffer: Xvfb.
Executing command /bin/bash
root@6d15153f5858:~#
</code>
And now you can execute any commands you want.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it. Now you should start developing Angular 2 applications more easily with <code>docker-compose</code>
and <code>angular-cli</code> by using <code>docker-angular-cli</code>.</p>

<p>You can follow the following tutorial to create a simple todo application: <a href="https://www.sitepoint.com/angular-2-tutorial/">https://www.sitepoint.com/angular-2-tutorial/</a></p>

<h2>8. Learn more</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/AngularClass/awesome-angular2">https://github.com/AngularClass/awesome-angular2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/timjacobi/angular2-education">https://github.com/timjacobi/angular2-education</a></li>
</ul>


<p>If you need any consultancy or outsourcing, don&rsquo;t hesitate to contact us. We&rsquo;re eager to build world class web
applications for you!</p>

<p>Happy developing!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
